<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CSU MSMB Group Study</title>
    <link>/</link>
      <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>CSU MSMB Group Study</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>CSU MSMB Group Study</title>
      <link>/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add your profile details to our course website</title>
      <link>/post/add-profile-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/add-profile-details/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;One goal of this course is to continue developing your data science programming
skills. This will include plenty of work on R programming, but also more work to
help you learn tools for reproducible research, like
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;RMarkdown&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34;&gt;git&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be using our course website as a collaboration tool during this course.
This website was created using &lt;a href=&#34;https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/&#34;&gt;blogdown&lt;/a&gt;,
which allows you to create and update a blogging website using R and RStudio. We
are using a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/geanders/csu_msmb&#34;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; to share
all the code for this website and serving the site using &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this course, you will have two graded products that you will need to
submit as blog posts to our site. One will be a glossary for one chapter of the
book, listing key words and their definitions for the chapter. The second is
the “official” version of one week’s in-course exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help get you up to speed with using blogdown, GitHub, and RMarkdown with
our site, we’ll start by having you update your profile details for our website.
This post covers the details for how to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;required-set-up&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Required set-up&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This exercise, and this course as a whole, requires a certain set-up
on your computer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R installed on your laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RStudio installed on your laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;git installed on your laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your own GitHub account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you already have all this set-up, you can skip to the next section of
the blog. Otherwise, this section has details on completing this set up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;install-r-on-your-laptop&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Install R on your laptop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can install R from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;Comprehensive R Archive Network (CRAN)&lt;/a&gt;.
Search for the version appropriate for your computer’s operating system. If you already
have R installed, check your version number. If it’s older than six months or so, you
should probably update your version for the class. You can use the &lt;code&gt;sessionInfo()&lt;/code&gt; function
to find out details about your current R session, including the version of R you’re
currently running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sessionInfo()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## R version 3.6.2 (2019-12-12)
## Platform: x86_64-apple-darwin15.6.0 (64-bit)
## Running under: macOS Mojave 10.14.6
## 
## Matrix products: default
## BLAS:   /Library/Frameworks/R.framework/Versions/3.6/Resources/lib/libRblas.0.dylib
## LAPACK: /Library/Frameworks/R.framework/Versions/3.6/Resources/lib/libRlapack.dylib
## 
## locale:
## [1] en_US.UTF-8/en_US.UTF-8/en_US.UTF-8/C/en_US.UTF-8/en_US.UTF-8
## 
## attached base packages:
## [1] stats     graphics  grDevices utils     datasets  methods   base     
## 
## loaded via a namespace (and not attached):
##  [1] compiler_3.6.2  magrittr_1.5    bookdown_0.16   tools_3.6.2    
##  [5] htmltools_0.4.0 yaml_2.2.0      Rcpp_1.0.3      stringi_1.4.5  
##  [9] rmarkdown_2.0   blogdown_0.17   knitr_1.26      stringr_1.4.0  
## [13] digest_0.6.23   xfun_0.12       rlang_0.4.2     evaluate_0.14&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the return from this call, for example, I can tell that I have
R version 3.6.2 (2019-12-12).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;install-rstudio-on-your-laptop&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Install RStudio on your laptop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download RStudio directly
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/&#34;&gt;from their website&lt;/a&gt;. The free
Desktop version will work great for this course. If your version of RStudio is
more than a year old, you should probably update it for this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;install-git-on-your-laptop&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Install git on your laptop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The software &lt;strong&gt;git&lt;/strong&gt; is version control software, which will help you record and
track changes that you’ve made to code and other plain text documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s free to download. Go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/downloads&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://git-scm.com/downloads&lt;/a&gt; and select the version
for your operating system. For this software, you’re probably okay if you
downloaded it a little while ago (although if more than two years or so, you might
want to update).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;get-a-github-account&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Get a GitHub account&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need a (free) GitHub account for this course. You can sign up for one
(if you don’t already have one) at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://github.com/&lt;/a&gt;. While there are some
fancier paid plans available, the free account will work great for this class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you sign up, you’ll get to choose a GitHub handle. You might want to make
this something that will be easy for people to remember. For example, if your
name is still available, that would be a great option. This handle will form
part of the address to all of your GitHub repositories, so it is convenient if
it is easy for people you work with to remember (mine, unfortunately, is not!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;about-blogdown&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;About &lt;em&gt;blogdown&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Add a brief description of blogdown / Hugo / static websites.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need to install two pieces of software to work on our
website. First, you’ll need the R package &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt;. You can install
this package in the normal way, using &lt;code&gt;install.packages&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;install.packages(&amp;quot;blogdown&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt;, you can install the Hugo software using a function
in the &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; package, &lt;code&gt;install_hugo&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(blogdown)
install_hugo()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For both these installations, your computer will need to be online or you’ll
get an error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;getting-a-fork-of-our-repository-on-your-computer&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Getting a fork of our repository on your computer&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All our websites files are posted in a GitHub repository at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/geanders/csu_msmb&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://github.com/geanders/csu_msmb&lt;/a&gt;. With this (or any) GitHub repository,
you can suggest changes by &lt;em&gt;forking&lt;/em&gt; the repository, cloning the fork to
your computer, making and commiting the changes, pushing those commits
back up to your fork of the repository on GitHub, and then submitting
a &lt;em&gt;pull request&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;forking-a-github-repository&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Forking a GitHub repository&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://giphy.com/embed/3o6fJ8baw3aDgUQnJu&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;giphy-embed&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://giphy.com/gifs/thegoodplace-season-2-nbc-3o6fJ8baw3aDgUQnJu&#34;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you &lt;strong&gt;fork&lt;/strong&gt; a GitHub repository, you get a copy of that repository that you
can play around with and change yourself, without it affecting the original
repository. It’s essentially just copying the whole repository, with all its
files, into a repository on your GitHub account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing that makes it different from a plain copy (and what makes it
really powerful in some cases) is that, if you decide that your changes might
make the &lt;em&gt;original&lt;/em&gt; repository better, you can submit a &lt;strong&gt;pull request&lt;/strong&gt;. This
requests that the owners of the original repository update it to incorporate the
changes you’ve made on your fork of the repository. The original authors can
review each of the &lt;strong&gt;commits&lt;/strong&gt; you’ve made, so they can even cherry-pick your
changes if they want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub also lets the original authors see if there are any &lt;strong&gt;merge conflicts&lt;/strong&gt;
created from changes that they’ve made to the original repository since you
forked it. This can let the original authors see how hard it will be to
incorporate all of your changes in the forked version with their version of the
repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fork the repository with our course’s website materials, all you’ll need to
do is go to our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/geanders/csu_msmb&#34;&gt;GitHub repository for the course
website&lt;/a&gt; (while you’re signed in to
GitHub) and click on the “Fork” button towards the right of the page. Now go and
check in the “Repositories” section of your own GitHub account—you should see that
you now have a forked copy of the “csu_msmb” repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this exercise, you’ll work with the fork of the repository, and then once you’ve
made your changes, you submit a pull request, so that we can get your changes
back into the main webpage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need more help on how to fork a repository, GitHub has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/en/github/getting-started-with-github/fork-a-repo&#34;&gt;help
page&lt;/a&gt;
on the topic that might be useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;cloning-the-fork-to-your-computer&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cloning the fork to your computer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, you’ll want to get a copy of your forked repository onto your own computer,
where you can work with it, make changes, and preview the website with your
updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this, you’ll &lt;strong&gt;clone&lt;/strong&gt; your fork of the repository onto your computer.
The version of the repository on GitHub is called the &lt;strong&gt;remote&lt;/strong&gt; branch of the
repository and the version you get on your computer once you’ve cloned it is
the &lt;strong&gt;local&lt;/strong&gt; branch. By cloning (instead of just downloading), you’ll maintain
a connection between the remote and local versions through git, which will allow
you to push changes that you make and commit on your own computer up to the
remote branch on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to GitHub, make sure you are logged into your account, and navigate to your
forked version of the repository for this class. There should be a button to the
right of the page that says “Clone or download” (you may need to scroll down to
find it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you click on this button, it will give you a choice between
“SSH” and “HTTPS” for the protocol to use to connect your local and remote branches
of the repository. You’re welcome to try either, but I usually (on a Mac) have
better luck with “SSH”. Occasionally, people running Windows in my courses have
had better luck with “HTTPS”, although for most folks “SSH” seems to work fine.
Once you choose which protocal to use, you can copy the snippet of code that is
given in the pop-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/github_clone_button.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, you’ll run this code from a &lt;strong&gt;bash shell&lt;/strong&gt; on your own computer to clone the
repository. You first will need to open a shell. If you’re on a Mac, you can do that
with the “Terminal” application. With Windows, you’ll probably need to use the
bash shell that comes with the Windows version of git. Search your programs for
“bash” or “git bash” and see if you see something that looks promising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you open a shell, you’ll see a command prompt, like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;username$&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can type &lt;strong&gt;shell commands&lt;/strong&gt; here and then press “Return” to run them. You
should first move into the directory where you want to clone the repository.
Your “Desktop” might be a good place for it for now (unless you have some
organization you use for course-related files). The &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; shell command lets you
“change directory”. If you don’t put anything after &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt;, it will change to
your &lt;strong&gt;home directory&lt;/strong&gt;. Otherwise, it will move to the directory you specify.
For example, if the “Desktop” directory is a subdirectory of my home directory,
I could move into it by running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd Desktop&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have not use shell commands much before and are having any problems
navigating to the directory you’d like, let us know in class, and one of us can
help you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you are in this directory, you’ll paste &lt;code&gt;git clone&lt;/code&gt; followed by the command
you copied from the “Clone or download” button on GitHub. It will probably look
something like this (but with your GitHub handle in place of “geanders”):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone git@github.com:geanders/csu_msmb.git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/bash_clone_git_repo.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you run this, you may have to put in your GitHub username and password. You
may also get some questions about whether you really want to download the
repository (you do). If everything’s successful, you should see that there’s a new
directory called “csu_msmb” in which directory you decided to put it (“Desktop”,
for example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need more help, GitHub has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/en/github/creating-cloning-and-archiving-repositories/cloning-a-repository&#34;&gt;help
page&lt;/a&gt;
with more on how to clone a repository from GitHub to your own computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;changing-and-committing-in-rstudio&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changing and committing in RStudio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;updating-your-profile-details&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Updating your profile details&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;rendering-blogdown-websites-in-rstudio&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rendering blogdown websites in RStudio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve opened the R Project with our website, you can use the
&lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; package to render the website. This will &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; update and
show the website on your computer (&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; change our main website online),
but it lets you check that everything’s working and preview what the
site will look like online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RStudio’s “Viewer” pane can work as a web browser. This means that it can
show our website. When you have opened the R Project with the cloned
repository of our website (“csu_msmb”), try running the following in your
R console to render the site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(blogdown)
serve_site()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/serve_site.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If everything worked, you should be able to see a version of the website in your
RStudio “Viewer” pane. If you’d like to see it in your usual web browser, click
on the “Show in new window” button on the top left of the “Viewer” pane. This
will open the website in your default web browser. Take a look at the web
address when you do—it should start with &lt;code&gt;127.0.0.1&lt;/code&gt;. This is a &lt;strong&gt;loopback
address&lt;/strong&gt;—an IP address that refers back to your local computer
(&lt;strong&gt;localhost&lt;/strong&gt;), rather than an outside web servers.
Anytime you’re building a website and checking it locally, you’ll see this as
the web address when you open the site in a web browser. (Should you want a
humourously geeky T-shirt, you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Theres-Place-127-0-0-1-Address-Geek/dp/B07PF54LYT/ref=pd_sbs_193_t_0/134-9564811-5189968?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;pd_rd_i=B07PF54LYT&amp;amp;pd_rd_r=8bcd759f-27a2-443f-a9b8-596744041403&amp;amp;pd_rd_w=hzmrB&amp;amp;pd_rd_wg=nlhQV&amp;amp;pf_rd_p=5cfcfe89-300f-47d2-b1ad-a4e27203a02a&amp;amp;pf_rd_r=S0HM3N9YTGK1JXEK2H3T&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;refRID=S0HM3N9YTGK1JXEK2H3T&#34;&gt;get one with “There’s no place like
127.0.0.1”&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you work through the next parts of the exercise, the rendered website in the
Viewer pane should update every time you save your changes to files in the
website. If you have the website open in your default browser, too, you might
want to refresh the site with the normal “Refresh” button for your browser.
If things ever seem like they’ve gotten out of sink, you can always re-run
&lt;code&gt;serve_site()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;navigating-the-websites-file-directory-to-find-your-profile&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Navigating the website’s file directory to find your profile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all have our own author profile in a subdirectory within the
website’s files. To find yours, go to the “content” subdirectory
of the website files and then the “authors” subdirectory within that.
You should see a subdirectory there with your name. Click on that
and you’ll see the two files that make up your author profile,
&#34;_index.md&#34; and “avatar.jpg”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/navigating_to_profile.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;updating-your-information-in-_index.md&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Updating your information in &#34;_index.md&#34;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your details are all given in the &#34;_index.md&#34; file in your author subdirectory.
To update your details on the website, you’ll need to change your details in this
file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The file is written in [YAML/TOML?]. Anywhere there is a placeholder, like
“[Year]” or “[Institution]”, replace the placeholder with your own information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/change_placeholders.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you change the following sections:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“bio”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“education”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“email”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“interests”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“name”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“organizations”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the sections in &lt;code&gt;social:&lt;/code&gt; are commented out, including the information
for buttons for GitHub, GoogleScholar, and Twitter. If you have accounts through
any of these services, you can add these buttons with your updated information.
Just delete the &lt;code&gt;#&lt;/code&gt; at the beginning of all lines in that section and then
change the handle or web address information so that it links to your
account for that service. In this section, also update your email address, with
&lt;code&gt;mailto:&lt;/code&gt; at the beginning, for the email icon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/update_social_section.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very bottom of the file, under the &lt;code&gt;---&lt;/code&gt;, provides space for you to write
a paragraph summarizing who you are and your academic / research interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/add_summary_paragraph.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to save the file after you’ve made all your changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an example of a completed &#34;_index.md&#34; file, you can see mine &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/geanders/csu_msmb/master/content/authors/brooke-anderson/_index.md&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;updating-your-avatar-picture&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Updating your avatar picture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s also a place in your author profile directory to include a photo to
represent yourself. To change from the default (the blue guy), replace the
“avatar.jpg” file in your author profile directory with the JPG of your choice,
and use &lt;em&gt;the same name&lt;/em&gt; (“avatar.jpg”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be helpful for you to use a photo of yourself, since that will help
us get to know each others’ names, but if you don’t have one or would prefer
not to use your own photo, feel free to pick any photo (for which you have
appropriate permissions) to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might need to crop your photo some to get it to show up in the circle on
the website correctly. Try with your uncropped picture once, check the website
in the RStudio Viewer pane to see how it looks, and then if it doesn’t work,
play around with cropping it until you’re happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;submitting-your-updates&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Submitting your updates&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;pushing-the-commits-back-to-github&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pushing the commits back to GitHub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;requesting-that-we-pull-your-changes&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Requesting that we pull your changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://giphy.com/embed/B6ZOD3aNT3Lxe&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;284&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;giphy-embed&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://giphy.com/gifs/cats-bowl-pull-B6ZOD3aNT3Lxe&#34;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips on writing a vocabulary list</title>
      <link>/post/tips-on-writing-a-vocabulary-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/tips-on-writing-a-vocabulary-list/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips on writing up the vocabulary list for a chapter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should include all words in the chapter that are given in bold. Be sure to
look for bolded terms in the sidenotes and end-of-chapter exercises, too! Occassionally,
the authors use bold for subheadings (see the “Why R and Bioconductor?” section in
the Introduction or the “Summary of this chapter” section of Chapter 1). These
subheadings do not need to be included in the vocabulary list for the chapter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is fine to use wording from the chapter text or to use wording directly from
other websites or sources. However, you &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; include a list of any of the
sources that you used to write your definitions at the bottom of the vocabulary
blog post. Further, if you are using sources besides the course textbook, make sure
that the definition is appropriate in the context of our course. Often, words will
have a number of different definitions across different disciplines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feel free to change a term from singular to plural or vice versa if it helps you
in writing the term’s definition. Similarly, if the bolded term does not include
all the words that would be helpful (e.g., the bolded term is “sufficient”, but
the term of interest is “sufficient statistic”), you can add a word or two to the
bolded term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can see an example of a vocabulary blog post for
&lt;a href=&#34;http://127.0.0.1:4736/post/vocabulary-for-chapter-1/&#34;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;. You can
use this as templates for your own post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be sure to include the tag “vocabulary”, as well as a tag for your chapter, on
the blog post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there are two bolded words that mean the same thing, put them both on the
vocabulary list (with the same definition).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a vocabulary term was defined in a previous chapter’s vocabulary list, feel free
to reuse the definition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our library has excellent resources that you can use to help write your definitions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vocabulary for Chapter 1</title>
      <link>/post/vocabulary-for-chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/vocabulary-for-chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped table-hover table-condensed&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
probability model
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
vector
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
discrete event
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
categorical variable
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A variable that can belong to one of a finite set of levels.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
levels
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In the context of a categorical variable, the set of groups to which the variable can be assigned.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
factor
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
exchangeable
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A way to describe a random variable for which the order that the data are observed doesn’t matter
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
sufficient statistic
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A statistic that, even though it is a summary, contains all the information that you would use from an original, uncondensed form of the data. An example is frequency counts for an exchangeable …
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
Bernoulli distribution
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A probability distribution to describe the outcome probability for two possible events.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
parameter
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A numerical value that describes a population or a model.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
complementary
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A description of two events who are mutually exclusive and whose probabilities sum to one. In other words, either one event or the other is guaranteed to happen, but not both.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
binomial random variable
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A variable whose values occur according to a binomial probability distribution.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
probability mass distribution
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
Poisson distribution
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A probability distribution that is appropriate when the probability of success is small and the number of trials is large.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
epitope
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
Site on a macromolecular antigen to which an antibody binds. This is the part of an antigen that is recognized by the immune system and is also known as an antigen determinent.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
Enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
An assay that is used to detect specific epitopes at different positions along a protein.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
conditional on
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
Given
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
cumulative distribution function
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
extreme value analysis
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
Analysis focused on the behavior of the very large or the very small values of a random distribution, allowing an exploration of the probability of rare events.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
rare events
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
Something that occurs with a very low probability.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
rank statistic
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A statistic based on the order of the relative positions of observations based on a certain characteristics.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
Monte Carlo method
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A method that uses a computer simulation based on our generative model that finds the probabilities of the events we’re interested in.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
probability or generative modeling
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A method of modeling where all the parameters are known and the mathematical theory allows us to work by deduction.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
deduction
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A top-down method of reasoning …
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
statistical modeling
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A method of modeling where the distribution of the data is not known.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
fit
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In the context of data and a statistical distribution, …
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
multinomial
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
power
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
The probability of detecting something if it is there.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
true positive rate
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
The probability of detecting something if it is there.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
null hypothesis
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
matrix
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
expected value
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
variability
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
statistic
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A numerical characteristic of a sample
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
null distribution
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
alternative
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In the context of a generating process, …
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
chi-squared distribution
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
p-value
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
The probability of seeing the data that were observed given a hypothesis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
probability density function
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
default
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In the context of function parameters for an R function, the value that is used if no custom value is specified.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
C. elegans genome nucleotide frequency
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
Bioconductor
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;sources-consulted-or-cited&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sources consulted or cited&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some of the definitions above are based in part or whole on listed definitions
in the following sources.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Holmes and Huber, 2019. &lt;em&gt;Modern Statistics for Modern Biology.&lt;/em&gt; Cambridge University Press,
Cambridge, United Kingdom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everitt and Skrondal, 2010. &lt;em&gt;The Cambridge Dictionary of Statistics (Fourth Edition).&lt;/em&gt; Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, United Kingdom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;practice&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Practice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://quizlet.com/473473135/flashcards/embed?i=2ldef3&amp;amp;x=1jj1&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; style=&#34;border:0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms</title>
      <link>/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/terms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
