<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>exercises | CSU MSMB Group Study</title>
    <link>/categories/exercises/</link>
      <atom:link href="/categories/exercises/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>exercises</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>exercises</title>
      <link>/categories/exercises/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create an exercise solution blog post</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-create-an-exercise-solution-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/how-to-create-an-exercise-solution-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Each of you will be responsible once or twice over the semester to create
a blog post that provides a clean, clearly-presented solution to the
in-class exercise for the week. This blog post provides the technical
instructions for writing and submitting that exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your exercise solution should be posted &lt;strong&gt;before&lt;/strong&gt; the next class meeting.
Since it will need to be reviewed by the faculty before it can be officially
posted, please plan to submit it by the &lt;strong&gt;Tuesday after&lt;/strong&gt; the class for your
exercise. Student assignments for the exercises are given in the
Schedule section of our course website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;overview-of-creating-a-post&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overview of creating a post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be submitting your exercise solution as a blog post. Creating
one for our website will follow all the same steps as creating a blog
post for a vocabulary list, just with different content. Please read
the &lt;a href=&#34;https://kind-neumann-789611.netlify.com/post/creating-a-vocabulary-list-blog-post/&#34;&gt;post on creating a vocabulary list&lt;/a&gt;
and follow the steps there to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update your fork of the website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a new blog post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use RMarkdown syntax to write the blog post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submit the blog post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;content-for-the-blog-post&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Content for the blog post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blog post should provide a walk-through of the solution to that week’s in-course
exercise. We have posted an example for &lt;a href=&#34;https://kind-neumann-789611.netlify.com/post/exercise-solution-for-chapter-1/&#34;&gt;the exercise for Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;
to give you an idea of what you should aim to write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, this exercise will be a resource for everyone in the class, to make sure
they’ve understood the exercise, as well as to see how someone else tackled the problem.
Your solution should cover all parts of the exercise (for example, if there’s a
part A and B, you should cover both). You can start by writing it as you would if you
were assigned the exercise as a homework problem, but then you should do a second step
of revision to provide some context and dig a bit deeper into how you tackled
the question. Since we are only requiring you to write up exercise answers once
or twice over the semester (rather than submitting homework for exercises every
week), we expect this product to be more in-depth and polished than a typical
homework solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, make sure that you have provided text explaining what the
exercise asks for, in case the reader hasn’t recently read the exercise prompt.
Second, please add a few details either about how you tackled the problem through code
or how the statistical principles covered in the exercise could apply to other problems
you’ve come across in your research or coursework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help in preparing your post, plan to spend the exercise time in class during the
week of your exercise visiting the different groups of students working on the
exercise. You can talk to them about how they’re approaching the problem, how they
interpret it, etc., to help you develop your own answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;tips&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be sure to refresh yourself on all the Markdown formatting tags you can use to improve
the appearance of your post. Be sure to include things like section headings and
italics or bold as appropriate. RStudio’s website has some nice cheatsheets on
RMarkdown that can help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure you include R code if appropriate. If you put parentheses around an
assignment expression in R, it will print out the assigned object and make the
assignment in the same call—you might find this useful in writing concise code
while still showing what’s in the objects you create.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the &lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;$$&lt;/code&gt; tags in RMarkdown to include mathematical equations in your blog post
when appropriate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you need to read in a dataset for R code in your blog post, talk with us about
how we can do that within a &lt;em&gt;blogdown&lt;/em&gt; framework. If your data comes from an online
source or from an R library, this shouldn’t be a problem, but if it is from a data file
that needs to be included in the website directory, we may need to work with you on
some extra set-up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are welcome to draw from (and cite) other statistics textbooks or dictionaries
if you’d like to in explaining the problem and your approach to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the code, look at vignettes and helpfiles, especially for packages you are not
familiar with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For a lot of Bioconductor packages, object-oriented programming is used pretty
heavily. This means that associated data in R packages will often be stored in a
format that you haven’t used yet. Look up more information on data classes used in
your exercise if you aren’t familiar with them. You can use the &lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt; function
to determine the class of an object as well as the name of the package that defines
that class. The &lt;code&gt;str&lt;/code&gt; function is often helpful for exploring a data object class, as well.
Many of the Bioconductor object classes will have special &lt;em&gt;accessor methods&lt;/em&gt;, which are
functions that allow you to extract certain elements from the object—check the helpfile
for the object class, as these methods are often listed there with examples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Googling can also be very helpful for learning more about functions, packages, and
datasets in R, especially if you don’t yet know what package the item is from.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most Bioconductor packages have very nice vignettes available online and from your
R session once you have installed the package. These are a great place to start to find
out more about how to use the functions and object classes that come with the package.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise solution for Chapter 1</title>
      <link>/post/exercise-solution-for-chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/exercise-solution-for-chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;This exercise asks us to explore the frequency of each of the four nucleotides
(A, C, G, and T) in the genome of &lt;em&gt;C. elegans&lt;/em&gt;, a type of worm used frequently
in scientific research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This solution requires that several R extension packages be loaded in your R
session. If you do not have these packages installed to your computer yet, you
should follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://kind-neumann-789611.netlify.com/post/chapter-1-exercise-setup/&#34;&gt;instructions we’ve posted
separately&lt;/a&gt;
describing the required set-up for this exercise. Once you have installed these
packages on your computer, you can load them into your current R session using
the &lt;code&gt;library&lt;/code&gt; function:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(&amp;quot;BSgenome.Celegans.UCSC.ce2&amp;quot;)
library(&amp;quot;Biostrings&amp;quot;)

library(&amp;quot;tidyverse&amp;quot;)
library(&amp;quot;knitr&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;part-a&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Part A&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part A of the question asks us to explore the nucleotide frequency of the &lt;em&gt;C.
elegans&lt;/em&gt; genome. This genome is available in the &lt;code&gt;Celegans&lt;/code&gt; data that comes with
the &lt;code&gt;BSgenome.Clegans.UCSC.ce2&lt;/code&gt; package and is stored within a &lt;code&gt;BSgenome&lt;/code&gt; class,
which is a special object class provided by the &lt;code&gt;Biostrings&lt;/code&gt; package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a dedicated function called &lt;code&gt;letterFrequency&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;code&gt;Biostrings&lt;/code&gt;
package that can be used to count the frequency of letters in a string (like a
genome) in an R object like this. In a call to this function, you must also
include the possible letters in your “alphabet”—that is, the possible letters
that each position in your string could take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;(nuc_freq &amp;lt;- letterFrequency(Celegans$chrM, letters=c(&amp;quot;A&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;C&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;G&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;T&amp;quot;)))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;##    A    C    G    T 
## 4335 1225 2055 6179&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To explore and plot this data, I put this summary data into a &lt;code&gt;tibble&lt;/code&gt;, so I
could more easily use &lt;code&gt;tidyverse&lt;/code&gt; tools with the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;nuc_freq_df &amp;lt;- tibble(nucleotide = names(nuc_freq), 
             n = nuc_freq)
nuc_freq_df&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## # A tibble: 4 x 2
##   nucleotide     n
##   &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt;      &amp;lt;int&amp;gt;
## 1 A           4335
## 2 C           1225
## 3 G           2055
## 4 T           6179&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this format, you can use &lt;code&gt;tidyverse&lt;/code&gt; tools to explore the data a bit more.
For example, you can determine the total number of nucleotides in the genome
and, with that calculate the proportion of each nucleotide across the genome.
Along with the &lt;code&gt;kable&lt;/code&gt; function from the &lt;code&gt;knitr&lt;/code&gt; package, I created a formatted
table with this information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;nuc_freq_df %&amp;gt;% 
  mutate(prop = n / sum(n)) %&amp;gt;% 
  kable(digits = 2, 
        caption = &amp;quot;Nucleotide frequencies and proportions in *C. elegans*&amp;quot;,
        col.names = c(&amp;quot;Nucleotide&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Frequency&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Proportion&amp;quot;))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;caption&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;tab:unnamed-chunk-4&#34;&gt;Table 1: &lt;/span&gt;Nucleotide frequencies and proportions in &lt;em&gt;C. elegans&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/caption&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;header&#34;&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nucleotide&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frequency&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Proportion&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;4335&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;0.31&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1225&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;0.09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;G&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;2055&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;0.15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;6179&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;0.45&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some presentations, it might be clearer to present this information in a
slightly different table format, using &lt;code&gt;pivot_longer&lt;/code&gt; and then &lt;code&gt;pivot_wider&lt;/code&gt; to
reformat the table for presentation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;nuc_freq_df %&amp;gt;% 
  mutate(prop = n / sum(n),
         n = prettyNum(n, big.mark = &amp;quot;,&amp;quot;),
         prop = prettyNum(prop, digits = 2)) %&amp;gt;% 
  pivot_longer(cols = c(&amp;quot;n&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;prop&amp;quot;)) %&amp;gt;% 
  pivot_wider(names_from = &amp;quot;nucleotide&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;% 
  mutate(name = case_when(
    name == &amp;quot;n&amp;quot; ~ &amp;quot;Frequency of nucleotide&amp;quot;,
    name == &amp;quot;prop&amp;quot; ~ &amp;quot;Proportion of all nucleotides&amp;quot;
  )) %&amp;gt;%  
  rename(` ` = name) %&amp;gt;% 
  kable(align = c(&amp;quot;rcccc&amp;quot;), 
        caption = &amp;quot;Nucleotide frequencies and proportions in *C. elegans*&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;caption&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;tab:unnamed-chunk-5&#34;&gt;Table 2: &lt;/span&gt;Nucleotide frequencies and proportions in &lt;em&gt;C. elegans&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/caption&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;header&#34;&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;A&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;C&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;G&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;T&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Frequency of nucleotide&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4,335&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1,225&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2,055&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;6,179&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Proportion of all nucleotides&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.31&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.089&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.45&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a plot of the frequency of each of the four nucleotides for the &lt;em&gt;C.
elegans&lt;/em&gt; nucleotide:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ggplot(nuc_freq_df, aes(x = nucleotide, y = n)) + 
  geom_col(fill = &amp;quot;lavender&amp;quot;, color = &amp;quot;black&amp;quot;) + 
  theme_classic() + 
  scale_y_continuous(label = scales::comma) + 
  theme(axis.title = element_blank()) + 
  labs(title = expression(paste(italic(&amp;quot;C. elegans&amp;quot;), &amp;quot; neucleotide frequency&amp;quot;)),
       caption = expression(paste(&amp;quot;Based on data from the &amp;quot;, italic(&amp;quot;BSgenome.Celegans.UCSC.ce2&amp;quot;), 
                                  &amp;quot; package.&amp;quot;)))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2020-02-11-exercise-solution-for-chapter-1_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-6-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This graph uses a few elements to improve its appearance that you might want to
explore if you’re not already familiar with them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;labs&lt;/code&gt; function is used to add both a title and a caption to the plot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;paste&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;expression&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;italic&lt;/code&gt; functions are used together to put “C.
elegans” and an R package name in italics in some of the labels on the plot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;scales&lt;/code&gt; package is used inside a scale layer for the &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt; code to
make the y-axis labels a bit nicer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;theme&lt;/code&gt; calls are used to apply a simpler overall theme than the default and to
remove the x- and y-axis titles (with &lt;code&gt;element_blank&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The color and fill of the bars are customized in the geom layer (&lt;code&gt;geom_col&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this plot, it certainly looks like the nucleotides are &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; uniformly
distributed in the &lt;em&gt;C. elegans&lt;/em&gt; genome. This question will be investigated more
in the next part of the exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;part-b&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Part B&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second part of the exercise asks us to test whether the observed nucleotide
data for &lt;em&gt;C. elegans&lt;/em&gt; is consistent with the uniform model that all nucleotide
frequencies are the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we can simulate several datasets under this null model and see how a plot
of nucleotide frequencies compares to the plot that we obtained with the observed
&lt;em&gt;C. elegans&lt;/em&gt; data. To make these plots, I first simulated 20 samples under the
null model that the distribution is uniform across the four nucleotides, using
the &lt;code&gt;rmultinom&lt;/code&gt; function with the &lt;code&gt;size&lt;/code&gt; argument set to the number of nucleotides in
the original &lt;em&gt;C. elegans&lt;/em&gt; genome data and the &lt;code&gt;prob&lt;/code&gt; argument set to have an equal
probability of each nucleotide at each spot on the genome:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;(sim_nuc_freq &amp;lt;- rmultinom(n = 20, 
                          size = sum(nuc_freq_df$n), 
                          prob = rep(1 / 4, 4)))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;##      [,1] [,2] [,3] [,4] [,5] [,6] [,7] [,8] [,9] [,10] [,11] [,12] [,13] [,14]
## [1,] 3545 3427 3397 3544 3516 3400 3503 3456 3480  3431  3387  3533  3434  3466
## [2,] 3322 3473 3437 3497 3425 3499 3445 3409 3431  3546  3335  3404  3412  3443
## [3,] 3466 3444 3506 3454 3470 3433 3421 3421 3344  3513  3531  3401  3496  3472
## [4,] 3461 3450 3454 3299 3383 3462 3425 3508 3539  3304  3541  3456  3452  3413
##      [,15] [,16] [,17] [,18] [,19] [,20]
## [1,]  3316  3444  3448  3418  3380  3562
## [2,]  3404  3419  3453  3484  3542  3378
## [3,]  3556  3526  3456  3421  3414  3461
## [4,]  3518  3405  3437  3471  3458  3393&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I moved this into a tibble so I could more easily rearrange and plot the data using
facetting in &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sim_nuc_freq_df &amp;lt;- as_tibble(sim_nuc_freq) %&amp;gt;% 
  mutate(nucleotide = c(&amp;quot;A&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;C&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;G&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;T&amp;quot;)) %&amp;gt;% 
  pivot_longer(-nucleotide, names_to = &amp;quot;sample&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;% 
  mutate(sample = sample %&amp;gt;% str_remove(&amp;quot;V&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;% as.numeric()) %&amp;gt;% 
  arrange(sample, nucleotide)

sim_nuc_freq_df %&amp;gt;% 
  slice(1:10)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## # A tibble: 10 x 3
##    nucleotide sample value
##    &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt;       &amp;lt;dbl&amp;gt; &amp;lt;int&amp;gt;
##  1 A               1  3545
##  2 C               1  3322
##  3 G               1  3466
##  4 T               1  3461
##  5 A               2  3427
##  6 C               2  3473
##  7 G               2  3444
##  8 T               2  3450
##  9 A               3  3397
## 10 C               3  3437&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ggplot(sim_nuc_freq_df, aes(x = nucleotide, y = value)) + 
  geom_col(fill = &amp;quot;lavender&amp;quot;, color = &amp;quot;black&amp;quot;) + 
  theme_classic() + 
  scale_y_continuous(label = scales::comma) + 
  theme(axis.title = element_blank()) + 
  labs(title = &amp;quot;Simulated neucleotide frequencies under a uniform model&amp;quot;) +
  facet_wrap(~ sample) + 
  expand_limits(y = max(nuc_freq_df$n))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2020-02-11-exercise-solution-for-chapter-1_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-8-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The y-axis limits were expanded here to cover the same range as that shown for the
observed &lt;em&gt;C. elegans&lt;/em&gt; nucleotide frequencies, to help make it easier to compare these plots
with the plot of our observed data. These plots of data simulated under the null model do
show some variation in frequencies among the nucleotides, but it’s certainly much less than
in the observed data for &lt;em&gt;C. elegans&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I repeated this simulation process, but I increased the number of simulations to 1,000:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sim_nuc_freq_df &amp;lt;- rmultinom(n = 1000, 
                          size = sum(nuc_freq_df$n), 
                          prob = rep(1 / 4, 4)) %&amp;gt;% 
  as_tibble() %&amp;gt;% 
  mutate(nucleotide = c(&amp;quot;A&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;C&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;G&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;T&amp;quot;)) %&amp;gt;% 
  pivot_longer(-nucleotide, names_to = &amp;quot;sample&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;% 
  mutate(sample = sample %&amp;gt;% str_remove(&amp;quot;V&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;% as.numeric()) %&amp;gt;% 
  arrange(sample, nucleotide)

sim_nuc_freq_df %&amp;gt;% 
  slice(1:10)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## # A tibble: 10 x 3
##    nucleotide sample value
##    &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt;       &amp;lt;dbl&amp;gt; &amp;lt;int&amp;gt;
##  1 A               1  3440
##  2 C               1  3461
##  3 G               1  3450
##  4 T               1  3443
##  5 A               2  3377
##  6 C               2  3449
##  7 G               2  3461
##  8 T               2  3507
##  9 A               3  3415
## 10 C               3  3438&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this dataframe of simulations, we can measure the mean, minimum, and maximum frequencies
of each nucleotide across all 1,000 simulations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;(sim_summary &amp;lt;- sim_nuc_freq_df %&amp;gt;% 
  group_by(nucleotide) %&amp;gt;% 
  summarize(mean_freq = mean(value),
            min_freq = min(value), 
            max_freq = max(value)))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## # A tibble: 4 x 4
##   nucleotide mean_freq min_freq max_freq
##   &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt;          &amp;lt;dbl&amp;gt;    &amp;lt;int&amp;gt;    &amp;lt;int&amp;gt;
## 1 A              3447.     3296     3594
## 2 C              3449.     3297     3671
## 3 G              3449.     3288     3624
## 4 T              3449.     3270     3618&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help compare this with the observed data, we can create a table with information from
both the original data and the simulations under the null model:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;nuc_freq_df %&amp;gt;% 
  left_join(sim_summary, by = &amp;quot;nucleotide&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;% 
  mutate_at(c(&amp;quot;mean_freq&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;min_freq&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;max_freq&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;n&amp;quot;), 
            prettyNum, big.mark = &amp;quot;,&amp;quot;, digits = 0) %&amp;gt;% 
  mutate(simulations = paste0(mean_freq, &amp;quot; (&amp;quot;, min_freq, &amp;quot;, &amp;quot;, max_freq, &amp;quot;)&amp;quot;)) %&amp;gt;% 
  select(nucleotide, n, simulations) %&amp;gt;% 
  kable(col.names = c(&amp;quot;Nucleotide&amp;quot;,              
        &amp;quot;Frequency in C. elegans genome&amp;quot;,
        &amp;quot;Mean frequency (minimum frequency, maximum frequency) across 1,000 simulations&amp;quot;), 
        align = &amp;quot;c&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;header&#34;&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Nucleotide&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Frequency in C. elegans genome&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Mean frequency (minimum frequency, maximum frequency) across 1,000 simulations&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4,335&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;3,447 (3,296, 3,594)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1,225&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;3,449 (3,297, 3,671)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;G&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2,055&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;3,449 (3,288, 3,624)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;6,179&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;3,449 (3,270, 3,618)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This helps clarify how unusual the observed data would be under the null model—the
counts of all four nucleotides in the &lt;em&gt;C. elegans&lt;/em&gt; genome are completely outside the
range of frequencies in the simulated data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way to look at this is with histograms of the distribution of frequencies
of each nucleotide under the null model compared to the observed frequencies in
the &lt;em&gt;C. elegans&lt;/em&gt; nucleotide:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ggplot(sim_nuc_freq_df, aes(x = value)) + 
  geom_histogram(binwidth = 10) + 
  facet_wrap(~ nucleotide) + 
  theme_classic() + 
  scale_x_continuous(name = &amp;quot;Frequency of nucleotide in the simulation under the null model&amp;quot;,
                     labels = scales::comma) + 
  scale_y_continuous(name = &amp;quot;# of simulations (out of 1,000)&amp;quot;) + 
  geom_vline(data = nuc_freq_df, aes(xintercept = n), color = &amp;quot;red&amp;quot;) + 
  labs(title = expression(paste(&amp;quot;Nucleotide frequency in &amp;quot;,
                                italic(&amp;quot;C. elegans&amp;quot;), 
                                &amp;quot; compared null model simulations&amp;quot;)),
       caption = &amp;quot;Red line shows the frequency observed for the nucleotide in C. elegans&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2020-02-11-exercise-solution-for-chapter-1_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-12-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, to help in answering this question, it would be interesting to look at a
single measure for each simulation (and for the observed data) rather than comparing
each nucleotide one at a time. Chapter 1 gives the equation for a statistic to
measure variability in multinomial data by calculating the sum of squares for the
differences between the observed and expected count of nucleotides for each of the
four nucleotides in a sample (p. 12).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I calculated this statistic for the observed data and then for each of the 1,000
simulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;(obs_stat &amp;lt;- nuc_freq_df %&amp;gt;% 
  mutate(expected = mean(n),
         stat_input = (n - expected) ^ 2 / expected) %&amp;gt;% 
  summarize(variability_stat = sum(stat_input)))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## # A tibble: 1 x 1
##   variability_stat
##              &amp;lt;dbl&amp;gt;
## 1            4387.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sim_stat &amp;lt;- sim_nuc_freq_df %&amp;gt;% 
  mutate(expected = mean(value), 
         stat_input = (value - expected) ^ 2 / expected) %&amp;gt;% 
  group_by(sample) %&amp;gt;% 
  summarize(variability_stat = sum(stat_input))

sim_stat %&amp;gt;% 
  slice(1:5)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## # A tibble: 5 x 2
##   sample variability_stat
##    &amp;lt;dbl&amp;gt;            &amp;lt;dbl&amp;gt;
## 1      1           0.0757
## 2      2           2.52  
## 3      3           0.715 
## 4      4           1.08  
## 5      5           1.31&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a plot of the distribution of this statistic across the 1,000 simulations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ggplot(sim_stat, aes(x = variability_stat)) + 
  geom_rect(data = sim_stat, aes(xmin = quantile(variability_stat, prob = 0.025),
                                 xmax = quantile(variability_stat, prob = 0.975),
                                 ymin = 0, ymax = Inf), 
            fill = &amp;quot;beige&amp;quot;, alpha = 0.5) +
  geom_histogram(bins = 30, fill = &amp;quot;white&amp;quot;, color = &amp;quot;tan&amp;quot;, alpha = 0.5) +
  theme_classic() + 
  labs(title = &amp;quot;Variability from expected values&amp;quot;,
       subtitle = &amp;quot;Values from simulations under the null&amp;quot;,
       x = &amp;quot;Value of variability statistic&amp;quot;, 
       y = &amp;quot;Number of simulations with given value&amp;quot;,
       caption = &amp;quot;The shaded yellow area shows the region of the central 95% of\nstatistic values for the 1,000 simulations under the null model.&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2020-02-11-exercise-solution-for-chapter-1_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-14-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The value of this statistic for the observed nucleotide frequencies for &lt;em&gt;C.
elegans&lt;/em&gt; is 4387, which is much larger (indicating greater variability
from expected values under the null model) than the value observed under most of
the simulations. It is, in fact, far outside the central 95% range of values
observed in simulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1 exercise setup</title>
      <link>/post/chapter-1-exercise-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/chapter-1-exercise-setup/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;The code instructions in the exercise statement appear to be outdated. The code below worked on my machine. Note that when asked whether I would like to update packages from the binary version, I said no. (When I said yes, &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; gave an error.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;if (!requireNamespace(&amp;quot;BiocManager&amp;quot;, quietly = TRUE))
  install.packages(&amp;quot;BiocManager&amp;quot;)
BiocManager::install(c(&amp;quot;Biostrings&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;BSgenome.Celegans.UCSC.ce2&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;BSgenome&amp;quot;))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see the various data genome data sets available by loading the &lt;code&gt;BSgenome&lt;/code&gt; library and typing &lt;code&gt;available.genomes()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have the needed packages installed, you can access the sequence data for this exercise via the following commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;suppressMessages(library(&amp;quot;BSgenome.Celegans.UCSC.ce2&amp;quot;))
Celegans&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## Worm genome:
## # organism: Caenorhabditis elegans (Worm)
## # provider: UCSC
## # provider version: ce2
## # release date: Mar. 2004
## # release name: WormBase v. WS120
## # 7 sequences:
## #   chrI   chrII  chrIII chrIV  chrV   chrX   chrM                              
## # (use &amp;#39;seqnames()&amp;#39; to see all the sequence names, use the &amp;#39;$&amp;#39; or &amp;#39;[[&amp;#39; operator
## # to access a given sequence)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;seqnames(Celegans)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## [1] &amp;quot;chrI&amp;quot;   &amp;quot;chrII&amp;quot;  &amp;quot;chrIII&amp;quot; &amp;quot;chrIV&amp;quot;  &amp;quot;chrV&amp;quot;   &amp;quot;chrX&amp;quot;   &amp;quot;chrM&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Celegans$chrM&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;##   13794-letter &amp;quot;DNAString&amp;quot; instance
## seq: CAGTAAATAGTTTAATAAAAATATAGCATTTGGGTT...TATTTATAGATATATACTTTGTATATATCTATATTA&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;class(Celegans$chrM)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## [1] &amp;quot;DNAString&amp;quot;
## attr(,&amp;quot;package&amp;quot;)
## [1] &amp;quot;Biostrings&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;length(Celegans$chrM)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## [1] 13794&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Biostrings packages provides functions to summarize the sequence. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(&amp;quot;Biostrings&amp;quot;)
lfM = letterFrequency(Celegans$chrM, letters=c(&amp;quot;A&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;C&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;G&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;T&amp;quot;))
lfM&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;##    A    C    G    T 
## 4335 1225 2055 6179&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sum(lfM)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## [1] 13794&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
