<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | CSU MSMB Group Study</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vocabulary for Chapter 4</title>
      <link>/post/vocabulary-for-chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/vocabulary-for-chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Chapter 4 covers how to generate both finite and infinite mixture models from various distributions. It introduces a number of terms relating to these models. The vocabulary words for Chapter 4 are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped table-hover table-condensed&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
finite mixture
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
data that contains a few components
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
infinite mixture
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
data that contains the same number of components as observations
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
bimodal distribution
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
distribution comprised of two peaks
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
expectation-maximization (EM) algorithm
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
an algorithm that allows for parameter estimation in proabailistic models with incomplete data
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
data augmentation
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
adding variables that are not measured (latent varibles) to the data
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
latent variable
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
variables not measured in the data
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
bivariate distribution
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
a combined distribution made of two random variables
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
marginal likelihood
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
sum of all possible values for the densitities
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
model averaging
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
the process of using several models and combining them together into a weighted model
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
zero inflated data
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
data that contains a large number of zero counts
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
point mass
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
a finite probabiliity concentrated at a point in the proability mass distribution at which there is a discontinuous segment in proability density function
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
sampling distribution
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
the probability distribution calculated from a random sample
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
bootstrap
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
an approximation of the true sampling distribution; created by drawing new samples from the empirical dstirubtion of the original sample
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
nonparametric bootstrap
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
an approximation of the true samplin distriubtion not based off of specific assumptionf or a particular model
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
negative binomial distribution/ gamma-Poisson distubtion
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
the probability distribution of the number of failures before the kth success in a sequence of Bernoulli trials
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
dispersion
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
the amount by which a set of observations deviate from their mean
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
variance-stabilizing transformations
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
transformations designed to give approximate independence between mean and variance
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
heteroscedasticity
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
the varaicne of the data is different in different regions of the data
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
delta method
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
a calculus procedure that uses random variables to approximate the expected value and variance of a function
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;sources-consulted-or-cited&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sources consulted or cited&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some of the definitions above are based in part or whole on listed definitions in the following sources.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Holmes and Huber, 2019. &lt;em&gt;Modern Statistics for Modern Biology.&lt;/em&gt; Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, United Kingdom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everitt and Skrondal, 2010. &lt;em&gt;The Cambridge Dictionary of Statistics (Fourth Edition).&lt;/em&gt; Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, United Kingdom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zero-Inflated Poisson Regression.&lt;/em&gt; Institute for Digital Research and Education Statistical Consulting. &lt;a href=&#34;https://stats.idre.ucla.edu/r/dae/zip/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://stats.idre.ucla.edu/r/dae/zip/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Berrar, 2019. &lt;em&gt;Introduction to Non-parametric Bootstrap.&lt;/em&gt; Research Gate. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://www.researchgate.net/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do and Batzoglou, 2008. &lt;em&gt;What is the expectaion maximization algorithm?.&lt;/em&gt; Nature Biotechnology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wikipedia: The Free Encylcopedia. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Main_Page&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Main_Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;practice&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Practice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://quizlet.com/485299672/match/embed?i=2r4ib&amp;amp;x=1jj1&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; style=&#34;border:0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips on writing a vocabulary list</title>
      <link>/post/tips-on-writing-a-vocabulary-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/tips-on-writing-a-vocabulary-list/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips on writing up the vocabulary list for a chapter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should include all words in the chapter that are given in bold. Be sure to
look for bolded terms in the sidenotes and end-of-chapter exercises, too! Occassionally,
the authors use bold for subheadings (see the “Why R and Bioconductor?” section in
the Introduction or the “Summary of this chapter” section of Chapter 1). These
subheadings do not need to be included in the vocabulary list for the chapter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you find one or more common synonyms for a term, you can include that with
the term in the list (e.g., “variability / spread / dispersion”).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is fine to use wording from the chapter text or to use wording directly from
other websites or sources. However, you &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; include a list of any of the
sources that you used to write your definitions at the bottom of the vocabulary
blog post. Further, if you are using sources besides the course textbook, make sure
that the definition is appropriate in the context of our course. Often, words will
have a number of different definitions across different disciplines. Try to use
more formal sources (e.g., textbooks, other published books) rather than less
formal websites to find definitions whenever possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feel free to change a term from singular to plural or vice versa if it helps you
in writing the term’s definition. Similarly, if the bolded term does not include
all the words that would be helpful (e.g., the bolded term is “sufficient”, but
the term of interest is “sufficient statistic”), you can add a word or two to the
bolded term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bolded terms in the book tend to favor statistical terms over biological ones.
If there are some biological terms you needed to look up when you read the chapter,
or that you think some people in the class might not know,
feel free to add them to your vocabulary list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can see an example of a vocabulary blog post for
&lt;a href=&#34;http://127.0.0.1:4736/post/vocabulary-for-chapter-1/&#34;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;. You can
use this as templates for your own post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be sure to include the tag “vocabulary”, as well as a tag for your chapter, on
the blog post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there are two bolded words that mean the same thing, put them both on the
vocabulary list (with the same definition).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a vocabulary term was defined in a previous chapter’s vocabulary list, feel free
to reuse the definition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our library has excellent resources that you can use to help write your definitions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add your profile details to our course website</title>
      <link>/post/add-profile-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/add-profile-details/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;One goal of this course is to continue developing your data science programming
skills. This will include plenty of work on R programming, but also more to
help you learn tools for reproducible research, like
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;RMarkdown&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34;&gt;git&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be using our course website as a collaboration tool during this course.
This website was created using &lt;a href=&#34;https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/&#34;&gt;blogdown&lt;/a&gt;,
which allows you to create and update a blogging website with R and RStudio. We
are using a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/geanders/csu_msmb&#34;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; to share
all the code for this website and serving the site using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.netlify.com/&#34;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this course, you will have two graded products that you will need to
submit as blog posts to our site. One will be a glossary of vocabulary terms for
one chapter of the book, listing key words and their definitions for the
chapter. The second will be the “official” version of one week’s in-course exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help get you up to speed with using blogdown, GitHub, and RMarkdown with
our site, we’ll start by having you update your profile details for our website.
We’ll also use this to give you all a chance to introduce yourselves to each
other and to us. This post covers the details for how to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;required-set-up&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Required set-up&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This exercise, and this course as a whole, requires a certain set-up
on your computer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R installed on your laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RStudio installed on your laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;git installed on your laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your own GitHub account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you already have all this set-up, you can skip to the next section.
Otherwise, this section has details on completing this set up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;install-r-on-your-laptop&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Install R on your laptop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can install R from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;Comprehensive R Archive Network (CRAN)&lt;/a&gt;.
Search for the version appropriate for your computer’s operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you already have R installed, check your version number. If it’s older than
six months or so, you should probably update your version for the class. You can
use the &lt;code&gt;sessionInfo()&lt;/code&gt; function to find out details about your current R
session, including the version of R you’re currently running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sessionInfo()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## R version 3.6.2 (2019-12-12)
## Platform: x86_64-w64-mingw32/x64 (64-bit)
## Running under: Windows 10 x64 (build 17134)
## 
## Matrix products: default
## 
## locale:
## [1] LC_COLLATE=English_United States.1252 
## [2] LC_CTYPE=English_United States.1252   
## [3] LC_MONETARY=English_United States.1252
## [4] LC_NUMERIC=C                          
## [5] LC_TIME=English_United States.1252    
## 
## attached base packages:
## [1] stats     graphics  grDevices utils     datasets  methods   base     
## 
## loaded via a namespace (and not attached):
##  [1] compiler_3.6.2  magrittr_1.5    bookdown_0.17   tools_3.6.2    
##  [5] htmltools_0.4.0 yaml_2.2.0      Rcpp_1.0.3      stringi_1.4.4  
##  [9] rmarkdown_2.1   blogdown_0.17   knitr_1.27      stringr_1.4.0  
## [13] digest_0.6.23   xfun_0.12       rlang_0.4.2     evaluate_0.14&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the return from this call, for example, I can tell that I have
R version 3.6.2 (2019-12-12).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;install-rstudio-on-your-laptop&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Install RStudio on your laptop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download RStudio directly
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/&#34;&gt;from their website&lt;/a&gt;. The free
Desktop version will work great for this course. If your version of RStudio is
more than a year old, you should probably update it for this course. To check
your version of R Studio, open R Studio, go to the “RStudio” tab at the top,
and click on “About RStudio”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;install-git-on-your-laptop&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Install git on your laptop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The software &lt;strong&gt;git&lt;/strong&gt; is version control software, which will help you record and
track changes that you’ve made to code and other plain text documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s free to download. Go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/downloads&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://git-scm.com/downloads&lt;/a&gt; and select the version
for your operating system. For this software, you’re probably okay if you
downloaded it a little while ago (although if more than two years or so, you might
want to update).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;get-a-github-account&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Get a GitHub account&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need a (free) GitHub account for this course. You can sign up for one
(if you don’t already have one) at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://github.com/&lt;/a&gt;. While there are some
fancier paid plans available, the free account will work great for this class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you sign up, you’ll get to choose a GitHub handle. You might want to make
this something that will be easy for people to remember. For example, if your
name is still available, that would be a great option. This handle will form
part of the address to all of your GitHub repositories, so it is convenient if
it is easy for people you work with to remember (mine, unfortunately, is not!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;about-blogdown&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;About &lt;em&gt;blogdown&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; package is an R package created by Yihui Xie that allows you
to use R and RStudio to create and update your own webpage with a blog. The
appeal of being able to do this with R is that you can write blog posts
using RMarkdown, so you can include executable R code in each post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; creates your site using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; framework.
Hugo is software that can build static websites (i.e., ones that can be
served to viewers without needing database backends or other fancy things).
People have created different templates for Hugo-generated websites, and these
templates provide the structure and framework, while you can adapt the content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that our website (which is, essentially, a collection of files in
a directory written in a form that a web browser can convert to a pretty
website) includes a lot of files and code that come straight from a template
that someone else wrote, and then places here and there where we can add or
change the files to make the website ours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the ways that you can change the website is to add posts. You’ll be
doing this later in the course by contributing two blog posts of your own,
one on the vocabulary for a chapter and one with the “official” version of
the exercise for a chapter. We’ll cover more on how to add a blog post later
in the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other way that you can change the website is to change some of its
“front page” data. The website has a section on “People”, with the
profiles of everyone in the class. The information shown in this section
is all saved in plain text files in our website’s file directory. Today,
you’ll change you details in the file dedicated to you and then send those
changes back to us so we can update the online version of the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need to install two pieces of software to work on our
website. First, you’ll need the R package &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt;. You can install
this package in the normal way, using &lt;code&gt;install.packages&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;install.packages(&amp;quot;blogdown&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt;, you can install the Hugo software using a function
in the &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; package, &lt;code&gt;install_hugo&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(blogdown)
install_hugo()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For both these installations, your computer will need to be online or you’ll
get an error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;getting-a-fork-of-our-repository-on-your-computer&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Getting a fork of our repository on your computer&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All our websites files are posted in a GitHub repository at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/geanders/csu_msmb&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://github.com/geanders/csu_msmb&lt;/a&gt;. With this (or any) GitHub repository,
you can suggest changes by &lt;strong&gt;forking&lt;/strong&gt; the repository, cloning the fork to
your computer, making and committing the changes, pushing those commits
back up to your fork of the repository on GitHub, and then submitting
a &lt;strong&gt;pull request&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;forking-a-github-repository&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Forking a GitHub repository&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://giphy.com/embed/3o6fJ8baw3aDgUQnJu&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;giphy-embed&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://giphy.com/gifs/thegoodplace-season-2-nbc-3o6fJ8baw3aDgUQnJu&#34;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you &lt;strong&gt;fork&lt;/strong&gt; a GitHub repository, you get a copy of that repository that you
can play around with and change yourself, without it affecting the original
repository. It’s essentially just copying the whole repository, with all its
files, into a repository on your GitHub account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing that makes it different from a plain copy (and what makes it
really powerful in some cases) is that, if you decide that your changes might
make the &lt;em&gt;original&lt;/em&gt; repository better, you can submit a &lt;strong&gt;pull request&lt;/strong&gt;. This
requests that the owners of the original repository update it to incorporate the
changes you’ve made on your fork of the repository. The original authors can
review each of the &lt;strong&gt;commits&lt;/strong&gt; you’ve made, so they can even cherry-pick your
changes if they want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub also lets the original authors see if there are any &lt;strong&gt;merge conflicts&lt;/strong&gt;
created from changes that they’ve made to the original repository since you
forked it. This can let the original authors see how hard it will be to
incorporate all of your changes in the forked version with their version of the
repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fork the repository with our course’s website materials, all you’ll need to
do is go to our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/geanders/csu_msmb&#34;&gt;GitHub repository for the course
website&lt;/a&gt; (while you’re signed in to
GitHub) and click on the “Fork” button towards the right of the page. Now go and
check in the “Repositories” section of your own GitHub account—you should see that
you now have a forked copy of the “csu_msmb” repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this exercise, you’ll work with the fork of the repository, and then once you’ve
made your changes, you submit a pull request, so that we can get your changes
back into the main webpage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need more help on how to fork a repository, GitHub has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/en/github/getting-started-with-github/fork-a-repo&#34;&gt;help
page&lt;/a&gt;
on the topic that might be useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;cloning-the-fork-to-your-computer&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cloning the fork to your computer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, you’ll want to get a copy of your forked repository onto your own computer,
where you can work with it, make changes, and preview the website with your
updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this, you’ll &lt;strong&gt;clone&lt;/strong&gt; your fork of the repository onto your computer.
The version of the repository on GitHub is called the &lt;strong&gt;remote&lt;/strong&gt; branch of the
repository and the version you get on your computer once you’ve cloned it is
the &lt;strong&gt;local&lt;/strong&gt; branch. By cloning (instead of just downloading), you’ll maintain
a connection between the remote and local versions through git, which will allow
you to push changes that you make and commit on your own computer up to the
remote branch on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to GitHub, make sure you are logged into your account, and navigate to your
forked version of the repository for this class. There should be a button to the
right of the page that says “Clone or download” (you may need to scroll down to
find it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you click on this button, it will give you a choice between
“SSH” and “HTTPS” for the protocol to use to connect your local and remote branches
of the repository. You’re welcome to try either, but I usually (on a Mac) have
better luck with “SSH”. Occasionally, people running Windows in my courses have
had better luck with “HTTPS”, although for most folks “SSH” seems to work fine.
Once you choose which protocol to use, you can copy the snippet of code that is
given in the pop-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/github_clone_button.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, you’ll run this code from a &lt;strong&gt;bash shell&lt;/strong&gt; on your own computer to clone the
repository. You first will need to open a shell. If you’re on a Mac, you can do that
with the “Terminal” application. With Windows, you’ll probably need to use the
bash shell that comes with the Windows version of git. Search your programs for
“bash” or “git bash” and see if you see something that looks promising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you open a shell, you’ll see a command prompt, like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;username$&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can type &lt;strong&gt;shell commands&lt;/strong&gt; here and then press “Return” to run them. You
should first move into the directory where you want to clone the repository.
Your “Desktop” might be a good place for it for now (unless you have some
organization you use for course-related files). The &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; shell command lets you
“change directory”. If you don’t put anything after &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt;, it will change to
your &lt;strong&gt;home directory&lt;/strong&gt;. Otherwise, it will move to the directory you specify.
For example, if the “Desktop” directory is a subdirectory of my home directory,
I could move into it by running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd Desktop&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have not use shell commands much before and are having any problems
navigating to the directory you’d like, let us know in class, and one of us can
help you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you are in this directory, you’ll paste &lt;code&gt;git clone&lt;/code&gt; followed by the command
you copied from the “Clone or download” button on GitHub. It will probably look
something like this (but with your GitHub handle in place of “geanders”):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone git@github.com:geanders/csu_msmb.git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/bash_clone_git_repo.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you run this, you may have to put in your GitHub username and password. You
may also get some questions about whether you really want to download the
repository (you do). If everything’s successful, you should see that there’s a new
directory called “csu_msmb” in which directory you decided to put it (“Desktop”,
for example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This directory has a special file in it that makes it an &lt;strong&gt;R Project&lt;/strong&gt;—a special
version of a file directory with some extra structure and saved preferences. Make
sure that you open the project as a whole when you work on it in R Studio, rather than
opening just by clicking on one of the files. To do this, you can go in R Studio
to &lt;code&gt;&#34;File&#34;&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;&#34;Open Project...&#34;&lt;/code&gt; and then navigate through your file directory
to the “csu_msmb” directory you just cloned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need more help, GitHub has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/en/github/creating-cloning-and-archiving-repositories/cloning-a-repository&#34;&gt;help
page&lt;/a&gt;
with more on how to clone a repository from GitHub to your own computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;changing-and-committing-in-rstudio&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changing and committing in RStudio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have R Studio open to an R Project that is using git version control,
R Studio will include a “Git” pane. You can use this pane to &lt;strong&gt;commit&lt;/strong&gt; changes you
make to files in the repository, write messages explaining those commits, and
&lt;strong&gt;push&lt;/strong&gt; your changes to your remote branch of the repository on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you commit a change, that change is written into a log of every change made
to the files in the repository. You can later look through these commits, so you’ll
want the commit messages to make sense when you read them in the future. When you’re
collaborating with others, the commit messages will help you see what each other
are doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you first commit a change, the commit is only saved in your local branch.
To send it up to the remote branch of the repository on GitHub, you’ll need to
&lt;strong&gt;push&lt;/strong&gt; those commits. Once you push your local commits, your GitHub repository
should exactly mirror your local repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as you make a change to a file in the repository that’s being track by
git, that file will show up in the Git pane, with a little check box beside it.
When you’re ready to commit a change, click on the “Commit” button on the top left
of the Git pane. This will open a pop-up box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this box, click the check boxes for all the changed files on the left you’d
like to include in the commit. Then write a short &lt;strong&gt;commit message&lt;/strong&gt;, describing
the changes you’ve made. You should try to fit it all in the first line of the
“commit message” window. If you can’t, write a short description in the first line,
skip a line, and then you can write as much as you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve written your commit message, click on the “commit” button. This will
record this commit. To check that it has, you can go to the “History” tab and
make sure the commit shows up as the last thing in your history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/committing.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;updating-your-profile-details&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Updating your profile details&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;rendering-blogdown-websites-in-rstudio&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rendering blogdown websites in RStudio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve opened the R Project with our website, you can use the
&lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; package to serve the website. This will &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; update and
show the website on your computer (&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; change our main website online),
but it lets you check that everything’s working and preview what the
site will look like online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RStudio’s “Viewer” pane can work as a &lt;strong&gt;web browser&lt;/strong&gt;. This means that it can
show our website. When you have opened the R Project with the cloned
repository of our website (“csu_msmb”), try running the following in your
R console to render the site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(blogdown)
serve_site()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/serve_site.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If everything worked, you should be able to see a version of the website in your
RStudio “Viewer” pane. If you’d like to see it in your usual web browser, click
on the “Show in new window” button on the top left of the “Viewer” pane (this
looks like a little rectangle with an arrow on it). This will open the website
in your default web browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the web address when you do—it should start with &lt;code&gt;127.0.0.1&lt;/code&gt;.
This is a &lt;strong&gt;loopback address&lt;/strong&gt;—an IP address that refers back to your local
computer (&lt;strong&gt;localhost&lt;/strong&gt;), rather than an outside web servers. Anytime you’re
building a website and checking it locally, you’ll see this in the web address
when you open the site in a web browser. (You can even &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Theres-Place-127-0-0-1-Address-Geek/dp/B07PF54LYT/ref=pd_sbs_193_t_0/134-9564811-5189968?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;pd_rd_i=B07PF54LYT&amp;amp;pd_rd_r=8bcd759f-27a2-443f-a9b8-596744041403&amp;amp;pd_rd_w=hzmrB&amp;amp;pd_rd_wg=nlhQV&amp;amp;pf_rd_p=5cfcfe89-300f-47d2-b1ad-a4e27203a02a&amp;amp;pf_rd_r=S0HM3N9YTGK1JXEK2H3T&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;refRID=S0HM3N9YTGK1JXEK2H3T&#34;&gt;get T shirts with “There’s no place like
127.0.0.1”&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you work through the next parts of the exercise, the rendered website in the
Viewer pane should update every time you save your changes to files in the
website. If you have the website open in your default browser, too, you might
want to refresh the site with the normal “Refresh” button for your browser.
If things ever seem like they’ve gotten out of sink, you can always re-run
&lt;code&gt;serve_site()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;navigating-the-websites-file-directory-to-find-your-profile&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Navigating the website’s file directory to find your profile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all have our own author profile in a subdirectory within the
website’s files. To find yours, go to the “content” subdirectory
of the website files and then the “authors” subdirectory within that.
You should see a subdirectory there with your name. Click on that
and you’ll see the two files that make up your author profile,
&#34;_index.md&#34; and “avatar.jpg”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/navigating_to_profile.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;updating-your-information-in-_index.md&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Updating your information in &#34;_index.md&#34;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your details are all given in the &#34;_index.md&#34; file in your author subdirectory.
To update your details on the website, you’ll need to change your details in this
file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The file is written in a Markup language called &lt;strong&gt;YAML&lt;/strong&gt;. If you’ve used RMarkdown
before, you might recognize this syntax from the information that goes at the
very top of each RMarkdown file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your &#34;_index.md&#34; file, anywhere there is a placeholder, like “[Year]”
or “[Institution]”, replace the placeholder with your own information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/change_placeholders.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be very careful when changing things like spaces and hyphens in the structure,
as YAML is based on parsing these elements. As with any Markup language, as
you are learning it, it’s best to try to render the final document often as
you make changes, so you can make sure the changes make it through like you want
and so you can catch any problems quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you change the following sections:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;bio:&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;education:&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;email:&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;interests:&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;name:&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;organizations:&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the sections in &lt;code&gt;social:&lt;/code&gt; are commented out, including the information
for buttons for GitHub, GoogleScholar, and Twitter. If you have accounts through
any of these services, you can add these buttons with your updated information.
Just delete the &lt;code&gt;#&lt;/code&gt; at the beginning of all lines in that section and then
change the handle or web address information so that it links to your
account for that service. In this section, also update your email address, with
&lt;code&gt;mailto:&lt;/code&gt; at the beginning, for the email icon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/update_social_section.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very bottom of the file, under the &lt;code&gt;---&lt;/code&gt;, provides space for you to write
a paragraph summarizing who you are and your academic / research interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/add_summary_paragraph.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to save the file after you’ve made all your changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an example of a completed &#34;_index.md&#34; file, you can see mine &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/geanders/csu_msmb/master/content/authors/brooke-anderson/_index.md&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;updating-your-avatar-picture&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Updating your avatar picture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s also a place in your author profile directory to include a photo to
represent yourself. To change from the default (the blue guy), replace the
“avatar.jpg” file in your author profile directory with the JPG of your choice,
and use &lt;em&gt;the same file name&lt;/em&gt; (“avatar.jpg”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be helpful for you to use a photo of yourself, since that will help
us put names with faces, but if you don’t have one or would prefer
not to use your own photo, feel free to pick any photo (for which you have
appropriate permissions) to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might need to crop your photo some to get it to show up in the circle on
the website correctly. Try with your uncropped picture once, check the website
in the RStudio Viewer pane to see how it looks, and then if it doesn’t work,
play around with cropping it until you’re happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;submitting-your-updates&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Submitting your updates&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;pushing-the-commits-back-to-github&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pushing the commits back to GitHub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you are ready to push all the changes you’ve committed to your local branch, you can
do this from the Git pane in R Studio. In this pane, there are two arrows: a green up
arrow and a blue down arrow. Click on the green up arrow to push the commits from your
computer (the local branch) to GitHub (the remote branch). Visit your GitHub page for
the repository (or refresh it if you already had it open) and check if your changes
have successfully been pushed to the remote branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t created an SSH key and shared it with GitHub, you may be asked
for your GitHub password every time you try to push. This will get to be a pain,
so you’ll probably want to set up an SSH key. For more on how to do this (as
well as other help with using RStudio with version control), check out
&lt;a href=&#34;https://support.rstudio.com/hc/en-us/articles/200532077-Version-Control-with-Git-and-SVN&#34;&gt;RStudio’s help documentation on the
topic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;requesting-that-we-pull-your-changes&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Requesting that we pull your changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://giphy.com/embed/B6ZOD3aNT3Lxe&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;284&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;giphy-embed&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://giphy.com/gifs/cats-bowl-pull-B6ZOD3aNT3Lxe&#34;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you’ve made changes, checked them, and pushed them to your GitHub version of
the repository. Remember, though, that you forked the repository from our original one, and
so you’ve been working with a copy of the repository this whole time, rather than changing
our original version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get your changes incorporated into our original version, you’ll need to request that we
&lt;strong&gt;pull&lt;/strong&gt; your changes into the original repository. To do this, you can submit a &lt;strong&gt;pull request&lt;/strong&gt;
through GitHub. Go to the main page for your fork of the GitHub repository and look for
a button that says “New pull request”. When you click this, it will walk you through making
a pull request. You’ll have a space to write a message describing the changes you’re
recommending in the pull request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like more details on this information, GitHub has &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/en/github/collaborating-with-issues-and-pull-requests/creating-a-pull-request&#34;&gt;help documentation
on pull
requests&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vocabulary for Chapter 1</title>
      <link>/post/vocabulary-for-chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/vocabulary-for-chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Chapter 1 covers generative modeling for discrete data. It introduces a number of terms covering
probablity and statistical modeling, as well as a few biological terms. The vocabulary words for
Chapter 1 are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped table-hover table-condensed&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
probability model
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A mathematical description of the possible outcomes of an experiment and the probability of each of those outcomes.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
vector
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In programming, a one-dimensional array of data, all with the same data type.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
discrete event
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In statistics, an event that can take a non-negative integer value (e.g., number of deaths in a community by day).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
categorical variable
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A variable that can belong to one of a finite set of levels.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
levels
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In the context of a categorical variable, the set of values to which the variable can be assigned.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
factor
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In the context of statistical programming, a data type that can take one of a limited number of possible values (e.g., sex, nationality).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
exchangeable
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A way to describe a random variable for which the order in which the data are observed doesn’t matter.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
sufficient statistic
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A statistic that, even though it is a summary, contains all the information that you would use from an original, uncondensed form of the data.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
Bernoulli distribution
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A probability distribution to describe the outcome probability for two possible events (e.g., win / loss).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
parameter
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A numerical value that describes a population or a model.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
complementary
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A description of two events who are mutually exclusive and whose probabilities sum to one (i.e., either one event or the other is guaranteed to happen, but not both).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
binomial random variable
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A variable whose values occur according to a binomial probability distribution.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
probability mass distribution
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A distribution giving the probability that a discrete random variable is equal to a given value.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
Poisson distribution
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A probability distribution that is appropriate when the probability of success is small and the number of trials is large.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
epitope / antigen determinent
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
Site on a macromolecular antigen to which an antibody binds. This is the part of an antigen that is recognized by the immune system.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
Enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
An assay that is used to detect specific epitopes at different positions along a protein.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
conditional on
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
Given
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
cumulative distribution function
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A distribution giving the probability that a random variable is less than given values.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
extreme value analysis
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
Analysis focused on the behavior of the very large or the very small values of a random distribution, allowing an exploration of the probability of rare events.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
rare event
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
Something that occurs with a very low probability.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
rank statistic
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A statistic based on the order of the relative positions of observations based on a certain characteristics.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
Monte Carlo method
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A method that uses a computer simulation based on a generative model to determine the probabilities of the events we’re interested in.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
probability or generative modeling
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A method of modeling where all the parameters are known and the mathematical theory allows us to work by deduction.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
deduction
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A top-down method of reasoning, starting from a theory or principle rather than from data.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
statistical modeling
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A method of modeling where the distribution of the data is not known.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
fit
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In the context of statistical modeling, estimating the parameters of a model based on observed data thought to be generated by the model.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
multinomial
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A generalization of the binomial distribution to cases where a certain number of outcomes can occur in each of a number of trials.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
power / true positive rate
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
The probability of detecting something if it is there.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
null hypothesis
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
Often, a hypothesis of “no association” that is used as a counterpart to a more interesting alternative hypothesis in hypothesis testing.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
matrix
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In programming, a two-dimensional array of data, all with the same data type.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
expected value
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
The predicted value of a variable.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
variability / spread / dispersion
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In statistics, the amount by which a set of observations deviate from their mean.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
statistic
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A numerical characteristic of a sample.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
null distribution
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
The probability distribution for the null hypothesis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
alternative
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In the context of a generating process, the generating process that is considered in comparison to the generating process under the null hypothesis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
chi-squared distribution
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A distribution often appropriate for assessing goodness-of-fit, including for models fit to contingency tables.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
p-value
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
The probability of seeing the data that were observed given a hypothesis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
probability density function
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A distribution giving the relative likelihood that a continuous random variable is equal to a given value.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
default
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In the context of function parameters for an R function, the value that is used if no custom value is specified.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
C. elegans genome nucleotide frequency
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
How often adenine, cytosine, guanine, and thymine occur in the DNA of a roundwork often used in scientific research.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
Bioconductor
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
Open-source software that provides contributed programs for bioinformatic data analysis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
codon
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A three-nucleotide sequence that specifies the amino acid to be created next (or to start or stop synthesis).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
DNA read
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
An inferred sequence of base pairs for a single DNA fragment, based on sequencing.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
nucleotide
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In the context of DNA, one of four compounds (adenine (A); cytosince (C); guanine (G); and tymine (T)) that make up the basic information unit.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
genome
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
An organism’s complete set of DNA, including all of its genes.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
replication cycle
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In biology, the process that begins with the infection of a host cell by a virus and ends with the release of mature progeny virus particles.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
point mutation
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A change, addition, or deletion of a single nucleotide in a gene sequence.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
genotype
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
The genetic make-up of an individual’s cells, including how the individual’s genetic make-up differs from others’.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
diploid
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
Having genetic material in two complete sets of chromosomes, from two parents.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
protein
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A compound made up of amino acids; one of the four types of macromolecules that make up living organisms.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
antibody
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A type of protein made by certain white blood cells in response to an antigen.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
antigen
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A foreign substance in the body to which the immune system reacts.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;sources-consulted-or-cited&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sources consulted or cited&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some of the definitions above are based in part or whole on listed definitions
in the following sources.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Holmes and Huber, 2019. &lt;em&gt;Modern Statistics for Modern Biology.&lt;/em&gt; Cambridge University Press,
Cambridge, United Kingdom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everitt and Skrondal, 2010. &lt;em&gt;The Cambridge Dictionary of Statistics (Fourth Edition).&lt;/em&gt; Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, United Kingdom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bioconductor: Open Source Software for Bioinformatics. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bioconductor.org/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://www.bioconductor.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wikipedia: The Free Encyclopedia. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Main_Page&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Main_Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIH Genetics Home Reference. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ghr.nlm.nih.gov/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://ghr.nlm.nih.gov/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NCI Dictionary of Cancer Terms. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cancer.gov/publications/dictionaries/cancer-terms&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://www.cancer.gov/publications/dictionaries/cancer-terms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;practice&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Practice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://quizlet.com/473473135/flashcards/embed?i=2ldef3&amp;amp;x=1jj1&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; style=&#34;border:0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
