<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vocabulary | CSU MSMB Group Study</title>
    <link>/categories/vocabulary/</link>
      <atom:link href="/categories/vocabulary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>vocabulary</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>vocabulary</title>
      <link>/categories/vocabulary/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips on writing a vocabulary list</title>
      <link>/post/tips-on-writing-a-vocabulary-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/tips-on-writing-a-vocabulary-list/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips on writing up the vocabulary list for a chapter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should include all words in the chapter that are given in bold. Be sure to
look for bolded terms in the sidenotes and end-of-chapter exercises, too! Occassionally,
the authors use bold for subheadings (see the “Why R and Bioconductor?” section in
the Introduction or the “Summary of this chapter” section of Chapter 1). These
subheadings do not need to be included in the vocabulary list for the chapter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you find one or more common synonyms for a term, you can include that with
the term in the list (e.g., “variability / spread / dispersion”).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is fine to use wording from the chapter text or to use wording directly from
other websites or sources. However, you &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; include a list of any of the
sources that you used to write your definitions at the bottom of the vocabulary
blog post. Further, if you are using sources besides the course textbook, make sure
that the definition is appropriate in the context of our course. Often, words will
have a number of different definitions across different disciplines. Try to use
more formal sources (e.g., textbooks, other published books) rather than less
formal websites to find definitions whenever possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feel free to change a term from singular to plural or vice versa if it helps you
in writing the term’s definition. Similarly, if the bolded term does not include
all the words that would be helpful (e.g., the bolded term is “sufficient”, but
the term of interest is “sufficient statistic”), you can add a word or two to the
bolded term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bolded terms in the book tend to favor statistical terms over biological ones.
If there are some biological terms you needed to look up when you read the chapter,
or that you think some people in the class might not know,
feel free to add them to your vocabulary list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can see an example of a vocabulary blog post for
&lt;a href=&#34;http://127.0.0.1:4736/post/vocabulary-for-chapter-1/&#34;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;. You can
use this as templates for your own post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be sure to include the tag “vocabulary”, as well as a tag for your chapter, on
the blog post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there are two bolded words that mean the same thing, put them both on the
vocabulary list (with the same definition).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a vocabulary term was defined in a previous chapter’s vocabulary list, feel free
to reuse the definition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our library has excellent resources that you can use to help write your definitions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create a vocabulary list blog post</title>
      <link>/post/creating-a-vocabulary-list-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/creating-a-vocabulary-list-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;As one of your assignments for this class, you are responsible for creating a blog
post with all the vocabulary and definitions for one week of the course. This
blog post will explain how you can create and publish that blog post on our
course website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;create-the-blog-post&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Create the blog post&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;update-your-fork-of-the-website&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Update your fork of the website&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should have already forked our website to add your details for the “Person”
section. You can use this same fork to add your blog post, but you should make sure
you get your fork up-to-date with the current version of the website before you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fork of a repository does not stay up-to-date with the original repository it
copied by itself. Instead, unless you update it, it will continue to be a snapshot
of the original repository (plus any changes you’ve made to your copy) as of
the time when you forked it. If the original has made a lot of changes since you
made your fork, it might be very hard to make a clean pull request as there will
be (potentially) lots of conflicts because of changes made to the original. It’s
considered polite to make sure that you’re working with an up-to-date fork of
a repository if you want to make a pull request back to the original.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Git code to update fork]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Updating your local branch]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;making-a-new-blog-post&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Making a new blog post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt;, each blog post is an RMarkdown document. The stuff at the very top
of the file (the YAML with details like the title and author) will look a bit
different than plain RMarkdown files, but once you get into the body of the post,
you should find that the rules are very similar to RMarkdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be creating a blog post that will include a table with the vocabulary
list as well as a few other elements. There are a few ways you can add a new
blog post file in &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt;. You’re welcome to use any method you’d like, but
if you’re not sure where to start, this is one way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure that you have RStudio open to the project for our course’s website. If you
do, you should see &lt;code&gt;csu_msmb&lt;/code&gt; in the upper right hand corner of your RStudio session.
(If not, go to &lt;code&gt;File&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Open Project...&lt;/code&gt; and navigate through your file directory
to your local version of our project directory and open the &lt;code&gt;csu_msmb.RProj&lt;/code&gt; file there.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, you can use an RStudio “Addin” to make a new blog post using a nice user
interface. These Addins are all alternatives to things you could do with a
function call in R, but the Addin often provides a more immediately
user-friendly interface for you to enter options. For example, the Addin for
creating a blog post does all the actions of a &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; function called
&lt;code&gt;new_post&lt;/code&gt;, but instead of needing to remember the parameter name to use for the
author listing and the title and all that, you can just fill the information
into a nice form and go from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find the new post Addin, look at the top of your RStudio session window. You
should see “Addins” with a down arrow beside it. Click on the down arrow. When
you do, you should see a “New Post” option. Select this option. A form should
pop up with spaces for you to fill in the title, author, and some other details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fill this form out in the following way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt; This should be “Vocabulary for Chapter [x]”, but with “[x]” replaced
with your chapter number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure you put your name exactly as listed in the “People” section
of the website. This will help the website generator connect this post with your
user profile, so when someone reads it they’ll get your picture and a link to
find out more about you at the end of the post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; This is where you put the publication date of your blog post, and it
has a pretty cool feature. Even if you write your blog post earlier, the post
will not be published on the blog &lt;em&gt;until&lt;/em&gt; the date listed in this section. That means
that you can start writing your blog on one day but know that it won’t show up online
until later. It also means you can start work on your blog, but a half-finished
draft won’t show up online until you get to the publication date. For right now,
set the current date in this section, so that your blog post will show up locally as
you work on it, but later you’ll actually change this date so that, when you submit
your pull request, your post won’t show up until the faculty have had the chance to
suggest some changes and for you to make any needed fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Categories and tags:&lt;/strong&gt; For both the “Categories” and the “Tags”, be sure to
include &lt;code&gt;vocabulary&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Chapter [x]&lt;/code&gt; (with [x] replaced with your chapter’s number).
These tags will let everyone on our website quickly find all the blog posts on your
chapter or all the vocabulary lists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Format:&lt;/strong&gt; You have several choices for the type of file to use to write your
blog post. Since we’re going to be using some R code to make the table look pretty,
you’ll need to pick one of the options that allows for R code chunks, so that rules
out plain Markdown. I recommend that you use “.Rmd”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you make these entries, click the button labeled “Done”. This creates an
RMarkdown file for your blog post and opens it for you. Here’s an example of
me doing this process if I were writing the vocabulary list for Chapter 16:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/post_addin.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see, in the RMarkdown file that’s created and opened, that all these
details end up getting inserted into the YAML at the top of the RMarkdown file.
If you ever need to change anything (like the date or the title), you can
change it here in the RMarkdown file. Do so carefully, though—YAML can be
pretty picky about things like spacing and special characters (hyphens, for
example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ever need to find this file later, all of the blog posts are saved in a
special place in our project’s directory: in the &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt; subdirectory, there’s
a subdirectory called &lt;code&gt;post&lt;/code&gt; that contains both the RMarkdown files used to
write the posts and the output (an HTML file) that is created by the RMarkdown
each time you save the file. You might notice that they all have long file
names—the file name for a blog post is a combinataion of its publication date
and its “slug”, which is some abbreviation of the original title. If you really
want, you can change what the slug will be when you first create the blog post,
but I don’t think you really need to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;writing-in-the-blog-post&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Writing in the blog post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the body of the blog post RMarkdown file (in other words, below the
&lt;code&gt;---&lt;/code&gt; that marks the end of the YAML section), you can write the blog post
just as you would any RMarkdown document. This means that you can use
things like &lt;code&gt;**&lt;/code&gt; to mark bold text, &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; for italics, and &lt;code&gt;#&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;##&lt;/code&gt;, etc., for
section headings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also means that you can insert chunks of R code that will run and add
their output within the post. Unlike in regular RMarkdown, you usually won’t
have to press the &lt;code&gt;Knit&lt;/code&gt; button to knit the document. Instead, the blog post
should re-knit every time you save the file. You can check to see by looking
at the &lt;code&gt;Viewer&lt;/code&gt; pane to look at the current version of the site (if it doesn’t
show the site automatically, load the &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; package and then run
&lt;code&gt;serve_site&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have not worked much with RMarkdown before, you might want to check
out some references on how it works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[RMarkdown references]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your blog post, go ahead and draft a first paragraph that describes the
key concepts covered in the chapter. Also, create third-level section headings
(i.e., use &lt;code&gt;###&lt;/code&gt; to mark the section heading) for “Sources consulted or cited”
and “Practice”. Save your blog post file and check to see if these changes
have been made in the version of the website in your &lt;code&gt;Viewer&lt;/code&gt; pane!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/start_post.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;create-the-vocabulary-list&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Create the vocabulary list&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;identify-the-vocabulary-terms-you-need-to-define&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Identify the vocabulary terms you need to define&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;create-a-.tsv-file-with-terms-and-definitions&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Create a .tsv file with terms and definitions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;adding-r-code-to-show-the-list-in-the-post&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Adding R code to show the list in the post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;creating-and-embedding-a-quizlet-app&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Creating and embedding a Quizlet app&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;submit-the-post&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Submit the post&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;pushing-your-changes-to-your-remote-repo&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pushing your changes to your remote repo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;submitting-a-pull-request-to-the-original-repo&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Submitting a pull request to the original repo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;edit-and-re-submit-the-post-based-on-faculty-feedback&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Edit and re-submit the post based on faculty feedback&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vocabulary for Chapter 16</title>
      <link>/post/vocabulary-for-chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/vocabulary-for-chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Chapter 16 does not exist, so it covers no topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;sources-consulted-or-cited&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sources consulted or cited&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;practice&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Practice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vocabulary for Chapter 1</title>
      <link>/post/vocabulary-for-chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/vocabulary-for-chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Chapter 1 covers generative modeling for discrete data. It introduces a number of terms covering
probablity and statistical modeling, as well as a few biological terms. The vocabulary words for
Chapter 1 are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped table-hover table-condensed&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
probability model
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A mathematical description of the possible outcomes of an experiment and the probability of each of those outcomes.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
vector
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In programming, a one-dimensional array of data, all with the same data type.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
discrete event
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In statistics, an event that can take a finite or countable number of values (e.g., number of deaths in a community by day).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
categorical variable
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A variable that can belong to one of a finite set of levels.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
levels
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In the context of a categorical variable, the set of values to which the variable can be assigned.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
factor
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In the context of statistical programming, a data type that can take one of a limited number of possible values (e.g., sex, nationality).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
exchangeable
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A property of a vector of random variables that implies the order in which the variables appear in the vector doesn’t matter.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
sufficient statistic
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A (summary) statistic that contains all the information about the model parameters that is in the original, uncondensed form of the data.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
Bernoulli distribution
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A probability distribution describing a random variable that can take on two possible outcomes (e.g., win / loss).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
parameter
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A numerical value that describes a population.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
complementary
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A description of two events who are mutually exclusive and whose probabilities sum to one (i.e., either one event or the other is guaranteed to happen, but not both).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
binomial random variable
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A variable whose values occur according to a binomial probability distribution.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
probability mass distribution
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A function giving the probability that a discrete random variable is equal to a given value.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
Poisson distribution
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A probability distribution for count data that has support on the non-negative integers. This distribution is also used to approximate a binomial distribution when the probability of success is small and the number of trials is large.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
epitope / antigen determinent
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
Site on a macromolecular antigen to which an antibody binds. This is the part of an antigen that is recognized by the immune system.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
Enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
An assay that is used to detect specific epitopes at different positions along a protein.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
conditional on
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
Given
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
cumulative distribution function
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A function giving the probability that a random variable is less than any specified value.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
extreme value analysis
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
Analysis focused on the behavior of the very large or the very small outcomes of a random distribution, allowing an exploration of the probability of rare events.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
rare event
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
Something that occurs with a very low probability.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
rank statistic
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A data vector sorted least to greatest.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
Monte Carlo method
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A method that uses computer simulation from a generative model to determine probabilities of events.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
probability or generative modeling
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A method of modeling where all the parameters are known and the mathematical theory allows us to work by deduction.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
deduction
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A top-down method of reasoning, starting from a theory or principle rather than from data.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
statistical modeling
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A method of modeling where the distribution of the data is not known.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
fit
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In the context of statistical modeling, estimating the parameters of a model based on observed data.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
multinomial
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A generalization of the binomial distribution to cases where there are a finite set of possible outcomes (e.g., a roll of a die).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
power / true positive rate
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
The probability of detecting something if it is there.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
null hypothesis
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
Often, a hypothesis of “no association” that is used as a counterpart to a more interesting alternative hypothesis in hypothesis testing.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
matrix
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In programming, a two-dimensional array of data, all with the same data type.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
expected value
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
The average (mean) value of a random variable.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
variability / spread / dispersion
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In statistics, the amount by which a set of observations deviate from their mean.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
statistic
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A numerical characteristic of a sample and known constants (i.e. no unknown parameters).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
null distribution
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
The probability distribution under the null hypothesis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
alternative
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In the context of a generating process and hypothesis testing, the generating process that is considered in comparison to the generating process under the null hypothesis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
chi-squared distribution
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A distribution on the non-negative real numbers that is often used in assessing goodness-of-fit (e.g. models fit to contingency tables).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
p-value
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
The probability of seeing the observed data or something more extreme under the generative model associated with the null hypothesis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
probability density function
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A function giving the relative likelihood that a continuous random variable is equal to a given value. When this function is integrated over the sample space, it equals 1.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
default
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In the context of arguments to an R function, the value that is used if no custom value is specified.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
C. elegans genome nucleotide frequency
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
How often adenine, cytosine, guanine, and thymine occur in the DNA of a roundwork often used in scientific research.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
Bioconductor
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
Open-source software that provides contributed programs for bioinformatic data analysis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
codon
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A three-nucleotide sequence that specifies the amino acid to be created next (or to start or stop synthesis).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
DNA read
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
An inferred sequence of base pairs for a single DNA fragment, based on sequencing.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
nucleotide
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In the context of DNA, one of four compounds (adenine (A); cytosince (C); guanine (G); and tymine (T)) that make up the basic information unit.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
genome
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
An organism’s complete set of DNA, including all of its genes.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
replication cycle
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
In biology, the process that begins with the infection of a host cell by a virus and ends with the release of mature progeny virus particles.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
point mutation
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A change, addition, or deletion of a single nucleotide in a gene sequence.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
genotype
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
The genetic make-up of an individual’s cells, including how the individual’s genetic make-up differs from others’.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
diploid
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
Having genetic material in two complete sets of chromosomes, from two parents.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
protein
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A compound made up of amino acids; one of the four types of macromolecules that make up living organisms.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
antibody
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A type of protein made by certain white blood cells in response to an antigen.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;font-weight: bold;border-right:1px solid;&#34;&gt;
antigen
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;width: 30em; &#34;&gt;
A foreign substance in the body to which the immune system reacts.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;sources-consulted-or-cited&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sources consulted or cited&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some of the definitions above are based in part or whole on listed definitions
in the following sources.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Holmes and Huber, 2019. &lt;em&gt;Modern Statistics for Modern Biology.&lt;/em&gt; Cambridge University Press,
Cambridge, United Kingdom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everitt and Skrondal, 2010. &lt;em&gt;The Cambridge Dictionary of Statistics (Fourth Edition).&lt;/em&gt; Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, United Kingdom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bioconductor: Open Source Software for Bioinformatics. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bioconductor.org/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://www.bioconductor.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wikipedia: The Free Encyclopedia. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Main_Page&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Main_Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIH Genetics Home Reference. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ghr.nlm.nih.gov/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://ghr.nlm.nih.gov/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NCI Dictionary of Cancer Terms. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cancer.gov/publications/dictionaries/cancer-terms&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://www.cancer.gov/publications/dictionaries/cancer-terms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;practice&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Practice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://quizlet.com/473473135/flashcards/embed?i=2ldef3&amp;amp;x=1jj1&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; style=&#34;border:0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
