<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>github | CSU MSMB Group Study</title>
    <link>/categories/github/</link>
      <atom:link href="/categories/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>github</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>github</title>
      <link>/categories/github/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create an exercise solution blog post</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-create-an-exercise-solution-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/how-to-create-an-exercise-solution-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Each of you will be responsible once or twice over the semester to create
a blog post that provides a clean, clearly-presented solution to the
in-class exercise for the week. This blog post provides the technical
instructions for writing and submitting that exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your exercise solution should be posted &lt;strong&gt;before&lt;/strong&gt; the next class meeting.
Since it will need to be reviewed by the faculty before it can be officially
posted, please plan to submit it by the &lt;strong&gt;Tuesday after&lt;/strong&gt; the class for your
exercise. Student assignments for the exercises are given in the
Schedule section of our course website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;overview-of-creating-a-post&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overview of creating a post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be submitting your exercise solution as a blog post. Creating
one for our website will follow all the same steps as creating a blog
post for a vocabulary list, just with different content. Please read
the &lt;a href=&#34;https://kind-neumann-789611.netlify.com/post/creating-a-vocabulary-list-blog-post/&#34;&gt;post on creating a vocabulary list&lt;/a&gt;
and follow the steps there to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update your fork of the website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a new blog post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use RMarkdown syntax to write the blog post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submit the blog post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;content-for-the-blog-post&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Content for the blog post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blog post should provide a walk-through of the solution to that week’s in-course
exercise. We have posted an example for &lt;a href=&#34;https://kind-neumann-789611.netlify.com/post/exercise-solution-for-chapter-1/&#34;&gt;the exercise for Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;
to give you an idea of what you should aim to write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, this exercise will be a resource for everyone in the class, to make sure
they’ve understood the exercise, as well as to see how someone else tackled the problem.
Your solution should cover all parts of the exercise (for example, if there’s a
part A and B, you should cover both). You can start by writing it as you would if you
were assigned the exercise as a homework problem, but then you should do a second step
of revision to provide some context and dig a bit deeper into how you tackled
the question. Since we are only requiring you to write up exercise answers once
or twice over the semester (rather than submitting homework for exercises every
week), we expect this product to be more in-depth and polished than a typical
homework solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, make sure that you have provided text explaining what the
exercise asks for, in case the reader hasn’t recently read the exercise prompt.
Second, please add a few details either about how you tackled the problem through code
or how the statistical principles covered in the exercise could apply to other problems
you’ve come across in your research or coursework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help in preparing your post, plan to spend the exercise time in class during the
week of your exercise visiting the different groups of students working on the
exercise. You can talk to them about how they’re approaching the problem, how they
interpret it, etc., to help you develop your own answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;tips&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be sure to refresh yourself on all the Markdown formatting tags you can use to improve
the appearance of your post. Be sure to include things like section headings and
italics or bold as appropriate. RStudio’s website has some nice cheatsheets on
RMarkdown that can help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure you include R code if appropriate. If you put parentheses around an
assignment expression in R, it will print out the assigned object and make the
assignment in the same call—you might find this useful in writing concise code
while still showing what’s in the objects you create.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the &lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;$$&lt;/code&gt; tags in RMarkdown to include mathematical equations in your blog post
when appropriate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you need to read in a dataset for R code in your blog post, save it in the
website directory’s “content/post/example_datasets” subdirectory. If your data
comes from an online source or from an R library, you won’t need to do this,
only if you need a “local” copy of the datafile to run your RMarkdown code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are welcome to draw from (and cite) other statistics textbooks or dictionaries
if you’d like to in explaining the problem and your approach to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the code, look at vignettes and helpfiles, especially for packages you are not
familiar with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For a lot of Bioconductor packages, object-oriented programming is used pretty
heavily. This means that associated data in R packages will often be stored in a
format that you haven’t used yet. Look up more information on data classes used in
your exercise if you aren’t familiar with them. You can use the &lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt; function
to determine the class of an object as well as the name of the package that defines
that class. The &lt;code&gt;str&lt;/code&gt; function is often helpful for exploring a data object class, as well.
Many of the Bioconductor object classes will have special &lt;em&gt;accessor methods&lt;/em&gt;, which are
functions that allow you to extract certain elements from the object—check the helpfile
for the object class, as these methods are often listed there with examples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Googling can also be very helpful for learning more about functions, packages, and
datasets in R, especially if you don’t yet know what package the item is from.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most Bioconductor packages have very nice vignettes available online and from your
R session once you have installed the package. These are a great place to start to find
out more about how to use the functions and object classes that come with the package.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create a vocabulary list blog post</title>
      <link>/post/creating-a-vocabulary-list-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/creating-a-vocabulary-list-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;As one of your assignments for this class, you are responsible for creating a blog
post with all the vocabulary and definitions for one week of the course. This
blog post will explain how you can create and publish that blog post on our
course website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;create-the-blog-post&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Create the blog post&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;update-your-fork-of-the-website&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Update your fork of the website&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should have already forked our website to add your details for the “Person”
section. You can use this same fork to add your blog post, but you should make sure
you get your fork up-to-date with the current version of the website before you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fork of a repository does not stay up-to-date with the original repository it
copied by itself. Instead, unless you update it, it will continue to be a snapshot
of the original repository (plus any changes you’ve made to your copy) as of
the time when you forked it. If the original has made a lot of changes since you
made your fork, it might be very hard to make a clean pull request as there will
be (potentially) lots of conflicts because of changes made to the original. It’s
considered polite to make sure that you’re working with an up-to-date fork of
a repository if you want to make a pull request back to the original.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To update your fork of the original repository, open your “csu_msmb.Rproj” file
to open our website’s R Project on your computer. This should open RStudio with
the website’s project open (check the top right corner of your RStudio window to
confirm—it should say “csu_msmb”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a little blue gear symbol in the “Git” pane in RStudio. Click on the down
arrow to the right of it and select “Shell…”. This should open a bash shell on
your computer. (If your computer uses Windows, there’s a chance that it might open
something other than a bash shell. In that case, you can change your preferences in
RStudio to reconfigure to always use a bash shell terminal when you ask for a shell
from RStudio.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this shell, you need to run two &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; commands. First, you’ll add a remote branch
to your repository. You already have one remote branch called “origin”—that’s the
GitHub repository that you have in your account, which you forked from the original.
Now you’ll add the &lt;em&gt;original&lt;/em&gt; (the GitHub repository in my account) as another remote
branch. Each branch has its own name, and you can use that name to refer to it in later
&lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; commands. The convention, if you add an original repository that you forked from
as a remote, is to name that remote branch “upstream”. Run the following code in your
bash shell to add the original GitHub repository as a remote branch with the name
“upstream”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;git remote add upstream git@github.com:geanders/csu_msmb.git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have added the original as a remote, you can pull in any commits that were
made to it since you originally forked it. There are a few ways you can do that, but one
way to do it in one step is with git’s &lt;code&gt;pull&lt;/code&gt; command. This fetches the changes and merges
them into your local version of the repository, all in one step. Run the following code in
your bash shell to do that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;git pull upstream master&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, all this will have worked seamlessly (if not, check with the faculty and we can
help you troubleshoot). Close your bash shell and check your version
of the “csu_msmb” project to see if it looks like it’s up-to-date with the original. You can
go to the “Commit” button in the “Git” tab, and there is a “History” selection in the window
that pops up. Look through that and make sure that you see recent commits to confirm that
your version is now up-to-date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, this has updated your local version, but not your GitHub remote. Go ahead and use the
green up arrow in RStudio’s “Git” pane to push your updated local version up to GitHub. Now
both your local (“master”) and remote (“origin”) branches should be up-to-date with our
original version, so it will make it much easier to merge in your changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to learn more about this process, there’s a really nice blog post
&lt;a href=&#34;https://philna.sh/blog/2018/08/21/git-commands-to-keep-a-fork-up-to-date/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;making-a-new-blog-post&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Making a new blog post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt;, each blog post is an RMarkdown document. The stuff at the very top
of the file (the YAML with details like the title and author) will look a bit
different than plain RMarkdown files, but once you get into the body of the post,
you should find that the rules are very similar to RMarkdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be creating a blog post that will include a table with the vocabulary
list as well as a few other elements. There are a few ways you can add a new
blog post file in &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt;. You’re welcome to use any method you’d like, but
if you’re not sure where to start, this is one way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure that you have RStudio open to the project for our course’s website. If you
do, you should see &lt;code&gt;csu_msmb&lt;/code&gt; in the upper right hand corner of your RStudio session.
(If not, go to &lt;code&gt;File&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Open Project...&lt;/code&gt; and navigate through your file directory
to your local version of our project directory and open the &lt;code&gt;csu_msmb.RProj&lt;/code&gt; file there.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, you can use an RStudio “Addin” to make a new blog post using a nice user
interface. These Addins are all alternatives to things you could do with a
function call in R, but the Addin often provides a more immediately
user-friendly interface for you to enter options. For example, the Addin for
creating a blog post does all the actions of a &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; function called
&lt;code&gt;new_post&lt;/code&gt;, but instead of needing to remember the parameter name to use for the
author listing and the title and all that, you can just fill the information
into a nice form and go from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find the new post Addin, look at the top of your RStudio session window. You
should see “Addins” with a down arrow beside it. Click on the down arrow. When
you do, you should see a “New Post” option. Select this option. A form should
pop up with spaces for you to fill in the title, author, and some other details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fill this form out in the following way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt; This should be “Vocabulary for Chapter [x]”, but with “[x]” replaced
with your chapter number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure you put your name exactly as listed in the “People” section
of the website. This will help the website generator connect this post with your
user profile, so when someone reads it they’ll get your picture and a link to
find out more about you at the end of the post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; This is where you put the publication date of your blog post, and it
has a pretty cool feature. Even if you write your blog post earlier, the post
will not be published on the blog &lt;em&gt;until&lt;/em&gt; the date listed in this section. That means
that you can start writing your blog on one day but know that it won’t show up online
until later. It also means you can start work on your blog, but a half-finished
draft won’t show up online until you get to the publication date. For right now,
set the current date in this section, so that your blog post will show up locally as
you work on it, but later you’ll actually change this date so that, when you submit
your pull request, your post won’t show up until the faculty have had the chance to
suggest some changes and for you to make any needed fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Categories and tags:&lt;/strong&gt; For both the “Categories” and the “Tags”, be sure to
include &lt;code&gt;vocabulary&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Chapter [x]&lt;/code&gt; (with [x] replaced with your chapter’s number).
These tags will let everyone on our website quickly find all the blog posts on your
chapter or all the vocabulary lists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Format:&lt;/strong&gt; You have several choices for the type of file to use to write your
blog post. Since we’re going to be using some R code to make the table look pretty,
you’ll need to pick one of the options that allows for R code chunks, so that rules
out plain Markdown. I recommend that you use “.Rmd”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you make these entries, click the button labeled “Done”. This creates an
RMarkdown file for your blog post and opens it for you. Here’s an example of
me doing this process if I were writing the vocabulary list for Chapter 16:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/post_addin.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see, in the RMarkdown file that’s created and opened, that all these
details end up getting inserted into the YAML at the top of the RMarkdown file.
If you ever need to change anything (like the date or the title), you can
change it here in the RMarkdown file. Do so carefully, though—YAML can be
pretty picky about things like spacing and special characters (hyphens, for
example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ever need to find this file later, all of the blog posts are saved in a
special place in our project’s directory: in the &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt; subdirectory, there’s
a subdirectory called &lt;code&gt;post&lt;/code&gt; that contains both the RMarkdown files used to
write the posts and the output (an HTML file) that is created by the RMarkdown
each time you save the file. You might notice that they all have long file
names—the file name for a blog post is a combinataion of its publication date
and its “slug”, which is some abbreviation of the original title. If you really
want, you can change what the slug will be when you first create the blog post,
but I don’t think you really need to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;writing-in-the-blog-post&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Writing in the blog post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://giphy.com/embed/XIqCQx02E1U9W&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;269&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;giphy-embed&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://giphy.com/gifs/XIqCQx02E1U9W&#34;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the body of the blog post RMarkdown file (in other words, below the
&lt;code&gt;---&lt;/code&gt; that marks the end of the YAML section), you can write the blog post
just as you would any RMarkdown document. This means that you can use
things like &lt;code&gt;**&lt;/code&gt; to mark bold text, &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; for italics, and &lt;code&gt;#&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;##&lt;/code&gt;, etc., for
section headings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also means that you can insert chunks of R code that will run and add
their output within the post. Unlike in regular RMarkdown, you usually won’t
have to press the &lt;code&gt;Knit&lt;/code&gt; button to knit the document. Instead, the blog post
should re-knit every time you save the file. You can check to see by looking
at the &lt;code&gt;Viewer&lt;/code&gt; pane to look at the current version of the site (if it doesn’t
show the site automatically, load the &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; package and then run
&lt;code&gt;serve_site&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have not worked much with RMarkdown before, you might want to check
out some references on how it works. There are several great articles on the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/articles.html&#34;&gt;RMarkdown website&lt;/a&gt; that can help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your blog post, go ahead and draft a first paragraph that describes the
key concepts covered in the chapter. Also, create third-level section headings
(i.e., use &lt;code&gt;###&lt;/code&gt; to mark the section heading) for “Sources consulted or cited”
and “Practice”. Save your blog post file and check to see if these changes
have been made in the version of the website in your &lt;code&gt;Viewer&lt;/code&gt; pane!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/start_post.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;create-the-vocabulary-list&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Create the vocabulary list&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, for the content of your post. You’ll be creating a vocabulary list, as well
as embedding a Quizlet practice app, so that your classmates can learn the
vocabulary for the chapter. This list will be what everyone is responsible for
in the weekly vocabulary quiz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see an example of a vocabulary blog post for
&lt;a href=&#34;https://kind-neumann-789611.netlify.com/post/vocabulary-for-chapter-1/&#34;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;. You can use
this as a template for your own post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;identify-the-vocabulary-terms-you-need-to-define&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Identify the vocabulary terms you need to define&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, you will need to decide which words from the chapter to define. We expect
that you will include &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; the bolded terms for your chapter.
Here are some guidelines for deciding on the vocabulary terms to define for your
chapter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should include all words in the chapter that are given in bold. Be sure to
look for bolded terms in the sidenotes and end-of-chapter exercises, too! Occassionally,
the authors use bold for subheadings (see the “Why R and Bioconductor?” section in
the Introduction or the “Summary of this chapter” section of Chapter 1). These
subheadings do not need to be included in the vocabulary list for the chapter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you find one or more common synonyms for a term, you can include that with
the term in the list (e.g., “variability / spread / dispersion”).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feel free to change a term from singular to plural or vice versa if it helps you
in writing the term’s definition. Similarly, if the bolded term does not include
all the words that would be helpful (e.g., the bolded term is “sufficient”, but
the term of interest is “sufficient statistic”), you can add a word or two to the
bolded term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bolded terms in the book tend to favor statistical terms over biological ones.
If there are some biological terms you needed to look up when you read the chapter,
or that you think some people in the class might not know,
feel free to add them to your vocabulary list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;create-a-.tsv-file-with-terms-and-definitions&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Create a .tsv file with terms and definitions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you could directly add the vocabulary into an RMarkdown table, we are asking you
to save it into a plain text &lt;code&gt;.tsv&lt;/code&gt; file, which will then be read into the RMarkdown
document to form a table. We doing this because it creates a few advantages. First,
if we have the vocabulary list in a dataframe (which we get when we read it in from
a plain text file), we can use some cool R packages to format the table nicely, without
having to learn loads of new Markdown or HTML formatting tricks. Second, we want to also
use the vocabulary list as input to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://quizlet.com/latest&#34;&gt;Quizlet&lt;/a&gt; list, which
will let us embed a practice app with flashcards and quizzes. One of the easiest ways
to create a Quizlet list is to copy in vocabulary list directly in the &lt;code&gt;tsv&lt;/code&gt; format,
so this approach makes that secondary use easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our website’s repository, there is a special subdirectory for saving vocabulary list
&lt;code&gt;.tsv&lt;/code&gt; files, with one for each chapter. In the Project directory, go to &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt;
&lt;code&gt;post&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;vocab_list&lt;/code&gt;. This is where you want to save the &lt;code&gt;.tsv&lt;/code&gt; file for your chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create the file, in RStudio go to the “File” tab in the menu at the top and select
“New File” -&amp;gt; “Text File”. This will open a file in RStudio in plain text format. Save the
file as “chapter_[x].tsv” (but replace “[x]” with your chapter number). Make sure you save
it in the “vocab_list” subdirectory of the project with the rest of the vocabulary list files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now write your vocabulary terms and definitions in this &lt;code&gt;.tsv&lt;/code&gt;. This file extension stands
for “tab-separated”, so to format the file correctly, you should:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put each term / definition pair on its own line. Because some terms will be long, they
may visibly “wrap” in the text file you have open, but as long as you don’t press the
“Return” key, they should still be on one line of the file. To doublecheck, you may want
to make sure that you have line-numbering on in RStudio and make sure that only one line
number is listed for each term on the left hand side of the file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press the “Tab” key to add a tab between the term and definition on each line. This should
be the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; place you have tabs in the file. R will look for tabs to figure out where to
split between vocabulary terms and there definitions (as will Quizlet when you copy the
terms into the list there). Sometimes it won’t look like the tab’s added a lot of space,
but that’s no problem—the computer can see it even if you can’t!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t put any header information at the start of the file. Just start directly with your
first vocabulary term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/make_vocab_tsv.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to see an example, check out the “chapter_1.tsv” file in the “vocab_lists”
subdirectory. This is the file that serves as input for the Chapter 1 vocabulary list
blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some guidelines for writing your definitions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is fine to use wording from the chapter text or to use wording directly from
other websites or sources. However, you &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; include a list of any of the
sources that you used to write your definitions at the bottom of the vocabulary
blog post. Further, if you are using sources besides the course textbook, make sure
that the definition is appropriate in the context of our course. Often, words will
have a number of different definitions across different disciplines. Try to use
more formal sources (e.g., textbooks, other published books) rather than less
formal websites to find definitions whenever possible. See the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://kind-neumann-789611.netlify.com/post/vocabulary-for-chapter-1/&#34;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt; vocabulary list
for an example of what we expect for using and listing references.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a vocabulary term was defined in a previous chapter’s vocabulary list, feel free
to reuse the definition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our library has excellent resources that you can use to help write your definitions,
including textbooks and dictionaries specific to biology and statistics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;adding-r-code-to-show-the-list-in-the-post&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Adding R code to show the list in the post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve written up some R code that will read in the vocabulary list and make it
into a nicely formatted table in the HTML version of the blog post. You can
re-use this R code in your post, you’ll just need to change the name of the
input file to the one for your chapter’s file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This R code uses a few R packages beyond the base R code. If you haven’t installed
these packages yet, you’ll need to before the code will run. You’ll need to install:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;knitr&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;dplyr&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;readr&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;kableExtra&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have these, below your paragraph summarizing the chapter’s theme, write:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The vocabulary words for Chapter [x] are:”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(but with your chapter’s number) and then paste in the following code and change
&lt;code&gt;chapter_1.tsv&lt;/code&gt; in the code to the correct file name for the .tsv file you created
for your chapter’s vocabulary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;```{r echo = FALSE, message = FALSE, warning = FALSE}
# Load packages
library(dplyr)
library(readr)
library(knitr)
library(kableExtra)

# Read in vocabulary from tsv into a dataframe
# This is where you&#39;ll need to replace the file name with your own
vocab &lt;- read_tsv(&#34;vocab_lists/chapter_1.tsv&#34;,
                  col_names = c(&#34;term&#34;, &#34;definition&#34;))

# Print the dataframe as a nice-looking table
vocab %&gt;% 
  kable(align = c(&#34;rl&#34;), 
        col.names = c(&#34;&#34;, &#34;&#34;)) %&gt;% 
  kable_styling(bootstrap_options = c(&#34;striped&#34;, &#34;hover&#34;,
                                      &#34;condensed&#34;)) %&gt;% 
  column_spec(1, bold = T, border_right = T) %&gt;%
  column_spec(2, width = &#34;30em&#34;)
```&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This code reads in the data from your .tsv file and then formats it in a nice way.
If you’d like to understand it better, try commenting out some lines and see how it
changes the output. One of my favorite piece of this code, one that I think might
come in useful for you later, is &lt;code&gt;column_spec(2, width = &#34;30em&#34;)&lt;/code&gt;. This sets the
width of one of the columns to be 30 ems (the width of the letter “m” in whatever
font you’re using). By setting the width, the table won’t automatically expand to
fit the text you put in the column onto one row. Instead, it will allow the text
to “wrap”, going onto separate lines if the definition entry is long enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to find out more about creating really fancy tables from RMarkdown,
check out the documentation on the &lt;code&gt;kableExtra&lt;/code&gt; package. What you can do (and how)
is different, depending on whether you’re outputting to a pdf or a HTML file, so there’s
separate documentation for each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you add this code in, I’ve found that you actually do need to press the &lt;code&gt;Knit&lt;/code&gt;
button sometimes. If you don’t see your list when you save your file, or if it doesn’t
update properly as you make changes to your file, try knitting with the &lt;code&gt;Knit&lt;/code&gt; button
and that should help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/add_vocab_code.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;creating-and-embedding-a-quizlet-app&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Creating and embedding a Quizlet app&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last piece of the blog post is the practice section. For this, you’ll create
a vocabulary list on &lt;a href=&#34;quizlet.com&#34;&gt;Quizlet&lt;/a&gt;, which you can then embed in the
blog post, so the other students can practice right on our site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll need to sign up for a Quizlet account first. The free account is fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, create a new vocabulary list. There’s a “Create” button for making new lists
on the main page. While you can add vocabulary by hand, you can also post in a
whole list if it’s in a tab-separated or comma-separated format. Copy in the contents
of your vocabulary list &lt;code&gt;.tsv&lt;/code&gt; file. You can preview the terms lower on the page
once you do, to make sure that all the terms and definitions came in correctly.
If everything looks good, click on the buttons for “Import” and then “Create”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will create your list and take you to a page where you can try out your
flashcards. On this page, there’s also a button with three dots. If you click on
this, there’s a choice of “Embed”. When you &lt;strong&gt;embed&lt;/strong&gt; HTML content, you are
inserting an application from one website within another one. Embedding is a
really fun trick for enriching blog posts and other RMarkdown documents that
are rendered to HTML. For example, you can also embed Shiny apps, YouTube
videos, and Google maps in your RMarkdown using the same process we’ll use here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you select “Embed”, a pop-up window will open with some HTML code. Copy
this and then paste it in the “Practice” section of your vocabulary blog post.
Be sure to leave a blank line above and below the text you paste. When you
look at your blog post in a web browser now, you should see the practice
flashcards embedded in the “Practice” section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/make_quizlet_app.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;submit-the-post&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Submit the post&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://giphy.com/embed/dOIDOBVNKmcFi&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;giphy-embed&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://giphy.com/gifs/blog-book-blaxk-dOIDOBVNKmcFi&#34;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, you’ve made these changes to your local copy of our website’s
repository. To submit the changes to us, you’ll need to push your changes
to your remote version of the repository (the one in &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; GitHub account)
and then submit a pull request to us for us to pull those changes into the
original website repository (the one in &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; GitHub account). This process
should feel pretty familiar—it’s pretty much what you did to submit your
changes to your profile information for the website on the first day of class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with other steps, there are several ways you can do this, and if you have an
idea of how to get it done, any way is fine. If you don’t know where to start,
though, you can follow along in this section for one way to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;pushing-your-changes-to-your-remote-repo&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pushing your changes to your remote repo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, you’ll need to get any changes you’ve made from your local
repository up to your remote version on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;commit&lt;/strong&gt; any changes that you’ve made through the &lt;code&gt;Git&lt;/code&gt; window in your
RStudio session. This will record the changes you’ve made in the &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; record
for your local repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, you’ll need to &lt;strong&gt;push&lt;/strong&gt; these commits to the remote repository, to send
these changes to GitHub. In the &lt;code&gt;Git&lt;/code&gt; window in RStudio, there’s a green up
button. Push that. It should send all your changes up to your GitHub version of
the repository. To check, go online to your GitHub account and look through
your repositories for your fork of “csu_msmb”. Click on “Commits” to see a
history of the commits to the repository—your latest ones should be at the top
of the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;submitting-a-pull-request-to-the-original-repo&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Submitting a pull request to the original repo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you’ve made changes, checked them, and pushed them to your GitHub version of
the repository. Remember, though, that you forked the repository from our original one, and
so you’ve been working with a copy of the repository this whole time, rather than changing
our original version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get your changes incorporated into our original version, you’ll need to request that we
&lt;strong&gt;pull&lt;/strong&gt; your changes into the original repository. To do this, you can submit a &lt;strong&gt;pull request&lt;/strong&gt;
through GitHub. Go to the main page for your fork of the GitHub repository and look for
a button that says “New pull request”. When you click this, it will walk you through making
a pull request. You’ll have a space to write a message describing the changes you’re
recommending in the pull request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like more details on this information, GitHub has &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/en/github/collaborating-with-issues-and-pull-requests/creating-a-pull-request&#34;&gt;help documentation
on pull
requests&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;edit-and-re-submit-the-post-based-on-faculty-feedback&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Edit and re-submit the post based on faculty feedback&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other faculty members and I will get a notice when you submit your pull request. We’ll
take a look and will probably have some suggestions for the wording of some of the
vocabulary terms. We’ll give you some feedback through the pull request page, and then
we’ll work together to get the list finalized before it’s published for the rest of the
class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add your profile details to our course website</title>
      <link>/post/add-profile-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/add-profile-details/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;One goal of this course is to continue developing your data science programming
skills. This will include plenty of work on R programming, but also more to
help you learn tools for reproducible research, like
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;RMarkdown&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34;&gt;git&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be using our course website as a collaboration tool during this course.
This website was created using &lt;a href=&#34;https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/&#34;&gt;blogdown&lt;/a&gt;,
which allows you to create and update a blogging website with R and RStudio. We
are using a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/geanders/csu_msmb&#34;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; to share
all the code for this website and serving the site using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.netlify.com/&#34;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this course, you will have two graded products that you will need to
submit as blog posts to our site. One will be a glossary of vocabulary terms for
one chapter of the book, listing key words and their definitions for the
chapter. The second will be the “official” version of one week’s in-course exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help get you up to speed with using blogdown, GitHub, and RMarkdown with
our site, we’ll start by having you update your profile details for our website.
We’ll also use this to give you all a chance to introduce yourselves to each
other and to us. This post covers the details for how to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;required-set-up&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Required set-up&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This exercise, and this course as a whole, requires a certain set-up
on your computer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R installed on your laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RStudio installed on your laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;git installed on your laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your own GitHub account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you already have all this set-up, you can skip to the next section.
Otherwise, this section has details on completing this set up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;install-r-on-your-laptop&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Install R on your laptop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can install R from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;Comprehensive R Archive Network (CRAN)&lt;/a&gt;.
Search for the version appropriate for your computer’s operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you already have R installed, check your version number. If it’s older than
six months or so, you should probably update your version for the class. You can
use the &lt;code&gt;sessionInfo()&lt;/code&gt; function to find out details about your current R
session, including the version of R you’re currently running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sessionInfo()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## R version 3.6.3 (2020-02-29)
## Platform: x86_64-apple-darwin15.6.0 (64-bit)
## Running under: macOS Mojave 10.14.6
## 
## Matrix products: default
## BLAS:   /Library/Frameworks/R.framework/Versions/3.6/Resources/lib/libRblas.0.dylib
## LAPACK: /Library/Frameworks/R.framework/Versions/3.6/Resources/lib/libRlapack.dylib
## 
## locale:
## [1] en_US.UTF-8/en_US.UTF-8/en_US.UTF-8/C/en_US.UTF-8/en_US.UTF-8
## 
## attached base packages:
## [1] stats     graphics  grDevices utils     datasets  methods   base     
## 
## loaded via a namespace (and not attached):
##  [1] compiler_3.6.3  magrittr_1.5    bookdown_0.18   tools_3.6.3    
##  [5] htmltools_0.4.0 yaml_2.2.1      Rcpp_1.0.4.6    stringi_1.4.6  
##  [9] rmarkdown_2.1   blogdown_0.18   knitr_1.28      stringr_1.4.0  
## [13] digest_0.6.25   xfun_0.13       rlang_0.4.5     evaluate_0.14&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the return from this call, for example, I can tell that I have
R version 3.6.3 (2020-02-29).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;install-rstudio-on-your-laptop&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Install RStudio on your laptop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download RStudio directly
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/&#34;&gt;from their website&lt;/a&gt;. The free
Desktop version will work great for this course. If your version of RStudio is
more than a year old, you should probably update it for this course. To check
your version of R Studio, open R Studio, go to the “RStudio” tab at the top,
and click on “About RStudio”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;install-git-on-your-laptop&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Install git on your laptop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The software &lt;strong&gt;git&lt;/strong&gt; is version control software, which will help you record and
track changes that you’ve made to code and other plain text documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s free to download. Go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/downloads&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://git-scm.com/downloads&lt;/a&gt; and select the version
for your operating system. For this software, you’re probably okay if you
downloaded it a little while ago (although if more than two years or so, you might
want to update).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;get-a-github-account&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Get a GitHub account&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need a (free) GitHub account for this course. You can sign up for one
(if you don’t already have one) at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://github.com/&lt;/a&gt;. While there are some
fancier paid plans available, the free account will work great for this class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you sign up, you’ll get to choose a GitHub handle. You might want to make
this something that will be easy for people to remember. For example, if your
name is still available, that would be a great option. This handle will form
part of the address to all of your GitHub repositories, so it is convenient if
it is easy for people you work with to remember (mine, unfortunately, is not!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;about-blogdown&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;About &lt;em&gt;blogdown&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; package is an R package created by Yihui Xie that allows you
to use R and RStudio to create and update your own webpage with a blog. The
appeal of being able to do this with R is that you can write blog posts
using RMarkdown, so you can include executable R code in each post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; creates your site using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; framework.
Hugo is software that can build static websites (i.e., ones that can be
served to viewers without needing database backends or other fancy things).
People have created different templates for Hugo-generated websites, and these
templates provide the structure and framework, while you can adapt the content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that our website (which is, essentially, a collection of files in
a directory written in a form that a web browser can convert to a pretty
website) includes a lot of files and code that come straight from a template
that someone else wrote, and then places here and there where we can add or
change the files to make the website ours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the ways that you can change the website is to add posts. You’ll be
doing this later in the course by contributing two blog posts of your own,
one on the vocabulary for a chapter and one with the “official” version of
the exercise for a chapter. We’ll cover more on how to add a blog post later
in the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other way that you can change the website is to change some of its
“front page” data. The website has a section on “People”, with the
profiles of everyone in the class. The information shown in this section
is all saved in plain text files in our website’s file directory. Today,
you’ll change you details in the file dedicated to you and then send those
changes back to us so we can update the online version of the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need to install two pieces of software to work on our
website. First, you’ll need the R package &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt;. You can install
this package in the normal way, using &lt;code&gt;install.packages&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;install.packages(&amp;quot;blogdown&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt;, you can install the Hugo software using a function
in the &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; package, &lt;code&gt;install_hugo&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(blogdown)
install_hugo()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For both these installations, your computer will need to be online or you’ll
get an error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;getting-a-fork-of-our-repository-on-your-computer&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Getting a fork of our repository on your computer&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All our websites files are posted in a GitHub repository at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/geanders/csu_msmb&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://github.com/geanders/csu_msmb&lt;/a&gt;. With this (or any) GitHub repository,
you can suggest changes by &lt;strong&gt;forking&lt;/strong&gt; the repository, cloning the fork to
your computer, making and committing the changes, pushing those commits
back up to your fork of the repository on GitHub, and then submitting
a &lt;strong&gt;pull request&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;forking-a-github-repository&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Forking a GitHub repository&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://giphy.com/embed/3o6fJ8baw3aDgUQnJu&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;giphy-embed&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://giphy.com/gifs/thegoodplace-season-2-nbc-3o6fJ8baw3aDgUQnJu&#34;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you &lt;strong&gt;fork&lt;/strong&gt; a GitHub repository, you get a copy of that repository that you
can play around with and change yourself, without it affecting the original
repository. It’s essentially just copying the whole repository, with all its
files, into a repository on your GitHub account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing that makes it different from a plain copy (and what makes it
really powerful in some cases) is that, if you decide that your changes might
make the &lt;em&gt;original&lt;/em&gt; repository better, you can submit a &lt;strong&gt;pull request&lt;/strong&gt;. This
requests that the owners of the original repository update it to incorporate the
changes you’ve made on your fork of the repository. The original authors can
review each of the &lt;strong&gt;commits&lt;/strong&gt; you’ve made, so they can even cherry-pick your
changes if they want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub also lets the original authors see if there are any &lt;strong&gt;merge conflicts&lt;/strong&gt;
created from changes that they’ve made to the original repository since you
forked it. This can let the original authors see how hard it will be to
incorporate all of your changes in the forked version with their version of the
repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fork the repository with our course’s website materials, all you’ll need to
do is go to our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/geanders/csu_msmb&#34;&gt;GitHub repository for the course
website&lt;/a&gt; (while you’re signed in to
GitHub) and click on the “Fork” button towards the right of the page. Now go and
check in the “Repositories” section of your own GitHub account—you should see that
you now have a forked copy of the “csu_msmb” repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this exercise, you’ll work with the fork of the repository, and then once you’ve
made your changes, you submit a pull request, so that we can get your changes
back into the main webpage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need more help on how to fork a repository, GitHub has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/en/github/getting-started-with-github/fork-a-repo&#34;&gt;help
page&lt;/a&gt;
on the topic that might be useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;cloning-the-fork-to-your-computer&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cloning the fork to your computer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, you’ll want to get a copy of your forked repository onto your own computer,
where you can work with it, make changes, and preview the website with your
updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this, you’ll &lt;strong&gt;clone&lt;/strong&gt; your fork of the repository onto your computer.
The version of the repository on GitHub is called the &lt;strong&gt;remote&lt;/strong&gt; branch of the
repository and the version you get on your computer once you’ve cloned it is
the &lt;strong&gt;local&lt;/strong&gt; branch. By cloning (instead of just downloading), you’ll maintain
a connection between the remote and local versions through git, which will allow
you to push changes that you make and commit on your own computer up to the
remote branch on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to GitHub, make sure you are logged into your account, and navigate to your
forked version of the repository for this class. There should be a button to the
right of the page that says “Clone or download” (you may need to scroll down to
find it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you click on this button, it will give you a choice between
“SSH” and “HTTPS” for the protocol to use to connect your local and remote branches
of the repository. You’re welcome to try either, but I usually (on a Mac) have
better luck with “SSH”. Occasionally, people running Windows in my courses have
had better luck with “HTTPS”, although for most folks “SSH” seems to work fine.
Once you choose which protocol to use, you can copy the snippet of code that is
given in the pop-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/github_clone_button.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, you’ll run this code from a &lt;strong&gt;bash shell&lt;/strong&gt; on your own computer to clone the
repository. You first will need to open a shell. If you’re on a Mac, you can do that
with the “Terminal” application. With Windows, you’ll probably need to use the
bash shell that comes with the Windows version of git. Search your programs for
“bash” or “git bash” and see if you see something that looks promising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you open a shell, you’ll see a command prompt, like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;username$&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can type &lt;strong&gt;shell commands&lt;/strong&gt; here and then press “Return” to run them. You
should first move into the directory where you want to clone the repository.
Your “Desktop” might be a good place for it for now (unless you have some
organization you use for course-related files). The &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; shell command lets you
“change directory”. If you don’t put anything after &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt;, it will change to
your &lt;strong&gt;home directory&lt;/strong&gt;. Otherwise, it will move to the directory you specify.
For example, if the “Desktop” directory is a subdirectory of my home directory,
I could move into it by running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd Desktop&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have not use shell commands much before and are having any problems
navigating to the directory you’d like, let us know in class, and one of us can
help you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you are in this directory, you’ll paste &lt;code&gt;git clone&lt;/code&gt; followed by the command
you copied from the “Clone or download” button on GitHub. It will probably look
something like this (but with your GitHub handle in place of “geanders”):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone git@github.com:geanders/csu_msmb.git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/bash_clone_git_repo.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you run this, you may have to put in your GitHub username and password. You
may also get some questions about whether you really want to download the
repository (you do). If everything’s successful, you should see that there’s a new
directory called “csu_msmb” in which directory you decided to put it (“Desktop”,
for example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This directory has a special file in it that makes it an &lt;strong&gt;R Project&lt;/strong&gt;—a special
version of a file directory with some extra structure and saved preferences. Make
sure that you open the project as a whole when you work on it in R Studio, rather than
opening just by clicking on one of the files. To do this, you can go in R Studio
to &lt;code&gt;&#34;File&#34;&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;&#34;Open Project...&#34;&lt;/code&gt; and then navigate through your file directory
to the “csu_msmb” directory you just cloned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need more help, GitHub has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/en/github/creating-cloning-and-archiving-repositories/cloning-a-repository&#34;&gt;help
page&lt;/a&gt;
with more on how to clone a repository from GitHub to your own computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;changing-and-committing-in-rstudio&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changing and committing in RStudio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have R Studio open to an R Project that is using git version control,
R Studio will include a “Git” pane. You can use this pane to &lt;strong&gt;commit&lt;/strong&gt; changes you
make to files in the repository, write messages explaining those commits, and
&lt;strong&gt;push&lt;/strong&gt; your changes to your remote branch of the repository on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you commit a change, that change is written into a log of every change made
to the files in the repository. You can later look through these commits, so you’ll
want the commit messages to make sense when you read them in the future. When you’re
collaborating with others, the commit messages will help you see what each other
are doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you first commit a change, the commit is only saved in your local branch.
To send it up to the remote branch of the repository on GitHub, you’ll need to
&lt;strong&gt;push&lt;/strong&gt; those commits. Once you push your local commits, your GitHub repository
should exactly mirror your local repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as you make a change to a file in the repository that’s being track by
git, that file will show up in the Git pane, with a little check box beside it.
When you’re ready to commit a change, click on the “Commit” button on the top left
of the Git pane. This will open a pop-up box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this box, click the check boxes for all the changed files on the left you’d
like to include in the commit. Then write a short &lt;strong&gt;commit message&lt;/strong&gt;, describing
the changes you’ve made. You should try to fit it all in the first line of the
“commit message” window. If you can’t, write a short description in the first line,
skip a line, and then you can write as much as you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve written your commit message, click on the “commit” button. This will
record this commit. To check that it has, you can go to the “History” tab and
make sure the commit shows up as the last thing in your history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/committing.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;updating-your-profile-details&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Updating your profile details&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;rendering-blogdown-websites-in-rstudio&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rendering blogdown websites in RStudio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve opened the R Project with our website, you can use the
&lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; package to serve the website. This will &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; update and
show the website on your computer (&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; change our main website online),
but it lets you check that everything’s working and preview what the
site will look like online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RStudio’s “Viewer” pane can work as a &lt;strong&gt;web browser&lt;/strong&gt;. This means that it can
show our website. When you have opened the R Project with the cloned
repository of our website (“csu_msmb”), try running the following in your
R console to render the site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(blogdown)
serve_site()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/serve_site.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If everything worked, you should be able to see a version of the website in your
RStudio “Viewer” pane. If you’d like to see it in your usual web browser, click
on the “Show in new window” button on the top left of the “Viewer” pane (this
looks like a little rectangle with an arrow on it). This will open the website
in your default web browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the web address when you do—it should start with &lt;code&gt;127.0.0.1&lt;/code&gt;.
This is a &lt;strong&gt;loopback address&lt;/strong&gt;—an IP address that refers back to your local
computer (&lt;strong&gt;localhost&lt;/strong&gt;), rather than an outside web servers. Anytime you’re
building a website and checking it locally, you’ll see this in the web address
when you open the site in a web browser. (You can even &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Theres-Place-127-0-0-1-Address-Geek/dp/B07PF54LYT/ref=pd_sbs_193_t_0/134-9564811-5189968?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;pd_rd_i=B07PF54LYT&amp;amp;pd_rd_r=8bcd759f-27a2-443f-a9b8-596744041403&amp;amp;pd_rd_w=hzmrB&amp;amp;pd_rd_wg=nlhQV&amp;amp;pf_rd_p=5cfcfe89-300f-47d2-b1ad-a4e27203a02a&amp;amp;pf_rd_r=S0HM3N9YTGK1JXEK2H3T&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;refRID=S0HM3N9YTGK1JXEK2H3T&#34;&gt;get T shirts with “There’s no place like
127.0.0.1”&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you work through the next parts of the exercise, the rendered website in the
Viewer pane should update every time you save your changes to files in the
website. If you have the website open in your default browser, too, you might
want to refresh the site with the normal “Refresh” button for your browser.
If things ever seem like they’ve gotten out of sink, you can always re-run
&lt;code&gt;serve_site()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;navigating-the-websites-file-directory-to-find-your-profile&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Navigating the website’s file directory to find your profile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all have our own author profile in a subdirectory within the
website’s files. To find yours, go to the “content” subdirectory
of the website files and then the “authors” subdirectory within that.
You should see a subdirectory there with your name. Click on that
and you’ll see the two files that make up your author profile,
&#34;_index.md&#34; and “avatar.jpg”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/navigating_to_profile.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;updating-your-information-in-_index.md&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Updating your information in &#34;_index.md&#34;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your details are all given in the &#34;_index.md&#34; file in your author subdirectory.
To update your details on the website, you’ll need to change your details in this
file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The file is written in a Markup language called &lt;strong&gt;YAML&lt;/strong&gt;. If you’ve used RMarkdown
before, you might recognize this syntax from the information that goes at the
very top of each RMarkdown file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your &#34;_index.md&#34; file, anywhere there is a placeholder, like “[Year]”
or “[Institution]”, replace the placeholder with your own information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/change_placeholders.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be very careful when changing things like spaces and hyphens in the structure,
as YAML is based on parsing these elements. As with any Markup language, as
you are learning it, it’s best to try to render the final document often as
you make changes, so you can make sure the changes make it through like you want
and so you can catch any problems quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you change the following sections:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;bio:&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;education:&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;email:&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;interests:&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;name:&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;organizations:&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the sections in &lt;code&gt;social:&lt;/code&gt; are commented out, including the information
for buttons for GitHub, GoogleScholar, and Twitter. If you have accounts through
any of these services, you can add these buttons with your updated information.
Just delete the &lt;code&gt;#&lt;/code&gt; at the beginning of all lines in that section and then
change the handle or web address information so that it links to your
account for that service. In this section, also update your email address, with
&lt;code&gt;mailto:&lt;/code&gt; at the beginning, for the email icon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/update_social_section.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very bottom of the file, under the &lt;code&gt;---&lt;/code&gt;, provides space for you to write
a paragraph summarizing who you are and your academic / research interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/screencapture_gifs/add_summary_paragraph.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to save the file after you’ve made all your changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an example of a completed &#34;_index.md&#34; file, you can see mine &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/geanders/csu_msmb/master/content/authors/brooke-anderson/_index.md&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;updating-your-avatar-picture&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Updating your avatar picture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s also a place in your author profile directory to include a photo to
represent yourself. To change from the default (the blue guy), replace the
“avatar.jpg” file in your author profile directory with the JPG of your choice,
and use &lt;em&gt;the same file name&lt;/em&gt; (“avatar.jpg”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be helpful for you to use a photo of yourself, since that will help
us put names with faces, but if you don’t have one or would prefer
not to use your own photo, feel free to pick any photo (for which you have
appropriate permissions) to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might need to crop your photo some to get it to show up in the circle on
the website correctly. Try with your uncropped picture once, check the website
in the RStudio Viewer pane to see how it looks, and then if it doesn’t work,
play around with cropping it until you’re happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;submitting-your-updates&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Submitting your updates&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;pushing-the-commits-back-to-github&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pushing the commits back to GitHub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you are ready to push all the changes you’ve committed to your local branch, you can
do this from the Git pane in R Studio. In this pane, there are two arrows: a green up
arrow and a blue down arrow. Click on the green up arrow to push the commits from your
computer (the local branch) to GitHub (the remote branch). Visit your GitHub page for
the repository (or refresh it if you already had it open) and check if your changes
have successfully been pushed to the remote branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t created an SSH key and shared it with GitHub, you may be asked
for your GitHub password every time you try to push. This will get to be a pain,
so you’ll probably want to set up an SSH key. For more on how to do this (as
well as other help with using RStudio with version control), check out
&lt;a href=&#34;https://support.rstudio.com/hc/en-us/articles/200532077-Version-Control-with-Git-and-SVN&#34;&gt;RStudio’s help documentation on the
topic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;requesting-that-we-pull-your-changes&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Requesting that we pull your changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://giphy.com/embed/B6ZOD3aNT3Lxe&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;284&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;giphy-embed&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://giphy.com/gifs/cats-bowl-pull-B6ZOD3aNT3Lxe&#34;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you’ve made changes, checked them, and pushed them to your GitHub version of
the repository. Remember, though, that you forked the repository from our original one, and
so you’ve been working with a copy of the repository this whole time, rather than changing
our original version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get your changes incorporated into our original version, you’ll need to request that we
&lt;strong&gt;pull&lt;/strong&gt; your changes into the original repository. To do this, you can submit a &lt;strong&gt;pull request&lt;/strong&gt;
through GitHub. Go to the main page for your fork of the GitHub repository and look for
a button that says “New pull request”. When you click this, it will walk you through making
a pull request. You’ll have a space to write a message describing the changes you’re
recommending in the pull request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like more details on this information, GitHub has &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/en/github/collaborating-with-issues-and-pull-requests/creating-a-pull-request&#34;&gt;help documentation
on pull
requests&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
